<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>👟 Athlete on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/</link><description>Recent content in 👟 Athlete on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/athlete/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bike Rain Gear</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/bike-rain-gear/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/bike-rain-gear/</guid><description>https://www.reddit.com/r/bikecommuting/comments/yhlipt/comment/iuej2t3/?utm_medium=android_app&amp;utm_source=share&amp;context=3</description></item><item><title>Choosing a Running Shoe</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/choosing-a-running-shoe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/choosing-a-running-shoe/</guid><description>Five big factors to consider:
Terrain Cushioning Gait Support Size Mileage Terrain Road-running shoes are generally light, flexible and even cushioning with flatter and smoother soles.
Trail-running shoes have bigger lugs to grip on unstable terrain, stronger underfoot and generally stiffer to handle uneven surfaces.
Cross-training shoes are thiner and simpler, to be used indoors for workouts and balance activities.
Cushioning The two main aspects are firmness and thickness of the foam between your feet and the ground.</description></item><item><title>Every Set of Weight Training Should Reach Muscle Failure</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/every-set-of-weight-training-should-reach-muscle-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/every-set-of-weight-training-should-reach-muscle-failure/</guid><description>Every set of exercise has a target range of repetitions. For example, a 3 x 8-12 or simply a 3 x 10 set - the standard set for muscle growth because Hypertrophy is Optimal at 8-12 Repetitions.
These sets should use a moderate weight (around 75% of the 1-rep maximum) such that you reach muscle failure - meaning you couldn&amp;rsquo;t execute another repetition no matter how much you wanted it.</description></item><item><title>Half-Kneeling Hip Flexor Stretches</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/halfkneeling-hip-flexor-stretches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/halfkneeling-hip-flexor-stretches/</guid><description>Get down into a half-kneeling position with your front and back knees at about a 90-degree angle. Your stance should be around shoulder-width apart and your pelvis should be facing forward. Squeeze the glute on the back leg and also engage your lower abdominals, trying to tuck the pelvis to flatten out your lower back. You may feel a stretch at the front of your hip on the kneeling side.</description></item><item><title>Heel to Toe Drop</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/heel-to-toe-drop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/heel-to-toe-drop/</guid><description>Heel-to-toe-drop is the height difference between
tornozelo e o dedão. Essa diferença muda a forma que o pé entra em contato com o chão na pisada. Um drop grande promove uma pisada retropé (rearfoot). Quanto menor o drop, mais o tênis vai estimular uma pisada mediopé (midfoot).
Então para quem tem canelite na parte superior da perna ou lesão no joelho, pode ser mais interessante escolher um tênis com um drop um pouco menor.</description></item><item><title>Hip Flexors</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/hip-flexors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/hip-flexors/</guid><description>The iliopsoas muscle is the strongest hip flexor group and consists of two muscles – the iliacus muscle and the psoas muscle. These muscles are separate in the abdomen but joins in the femur at the lesser trochanter.
The rectus femoris muscle is one of four quadriceps muscles, but is the only one of that muscle group that crosses the hip joint and acts as a hip flexor (as well as knee extensor).</description></item><item><title>Hypertrophy is Optimal at 8-12 Repetitions</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/hypertrophy-is-optimal-at-812-repetitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/hypertrophy-is-optimal-at-812-repetitions/</guid><description>1-5 reps primarily develop strength, with more impact on muscle size and none on endurance. 6-12 reps develop a balance of strength, muscle size and endurance. 13-20 reps develop endurance, with some increases to muscle size and limited impact on strength.
Total mechanical tension, which is a key hypertrophy stimulus, can be maximized through moderate relative loads (e.g. 75% of 1RM) and high volume training (e.g. 10 sets of 10 reps) in comparison with high relative loads (e.</description></item><item><title>Joint Mobility Work Is Required Daily</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/joint-mobility-work-is-required-daily/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/joint-mobility-work-is-required-daily/</guid><description>Joint mobility work is necessary and should be done every morning. If you have a popping or creaking joint, double the work. If it is painful, move slower, consult with a professional and - with his consent - triple the work.
Because Every Set of Weight Training Should Reach Muscle Failure, joints are under a lot of stress during weight training. It is good to warm up before workouts, but it&amp;rsquo;s also good to do mobility work as a totally separate (earlier) session.</description></item><item><title>Runner's Knee</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-knee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-knee/</guid><description>Runner&amp;rsquo;s Knee is an umbrella term for several conditions that can cause discomfort or pain around the knee cap or the patella region.
Any activity that stresses the knee joint can cause.
A dull or aching feeling above, below or behind the knee cap. May experience swelling, cracking, popping or grinding sensation.
Irritation of the soft tissue or lining of the knee, worn or torn cartilage or strained tendons.
How to prevent it?</description></item><item><title>Runner's Loop</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-loop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-loop/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Running Shoe Whishlist</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/running-shoe-whishlist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/running-shoe-whishlist/</guid><description>Experimentar Nike Air Zoom Pegasus 38
Adidas Ultraboost 21
Fila Float Fly: 279
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-fila-float-fly-feminino-953275.html?cor=4P
ASICS Gel nimbus 23
Nike ZoomX Invincible Run
Nike ZoomX Next% 2
Sketchers Go Run Max Road 4
ON Cloudflyer
300 km
600 km / 300 km
900 km / 600 km / 300 km
Reddit
New Balance Rebel V2: 799,99 - 210g - 6mm
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-new-balance-rebel-v2-corrida-masculino-m0irr8-mktp.html?cor=31
New Balance 1080v11: 999,99 - 285g - 8mm
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-new-balance-1080v11---masculino-m0il8v-mktp.html?cor=06
https://www.decathlon.com.br/tenis-de-corrida-masculino-1080v11-102000/p</description></item><item><title>Training Plan - Hero</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--hero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--hero/</guid><description>This is a training plan
1 rest day after Easy Run 2 rest days after Speed Run 2 rest days after Long Run Easy Run Speed Run Long Run 40m easy 50m Fartlek 50m long 30m easy 50m Fartlek 40m long Workout Type Pace Time Recovery Jog 6:48 - 7:19 Long Runs 6:12 - 6:58 Easy Runs 6:10 - 6:43 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Steady Run 5:47 - 6:02 Tempo Run 5:34 - 5:45 Intervals 5:28 - 5:39 #TODO 25 Minute 5K Guide</description></item><item><title>Training Plan - Walker</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--walker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--walker/</guid><description>This is a training plan for absolute starters or those recovering from injury. The focus is on getting the joints ready for higher intensity workouts as safely as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s much better to progress slowly and surely than to risk having to start all over again.
#TODO organize
Stretch a lot.
Half-Kneeling Hip Flexor Stretches The glute stretch Lie face up in the floor with knees and hips bent Place your right ankle across your left thigh Grab your left thigh with both hands and pull gently towards chest hold for 20 to 30 seconds and then switch sides</description></item></channel></rss>