<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/</link><description>Recent content on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>_Roadmap</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/_roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/_roadmap/</guid><description>The Tools Pans &amp;amp; Pots Cast-Iron Maintenance Carbon Steel Maintenance Cutting Tools</description></item><item><title>_Roadmap</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/_roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/_roadmap/</guid><description>Topics Lighting and Shot Composition Focus and Depth of Field Editing on Adobe Lightroom Portrait Editing Technique Exposure Contrast Highlights/Shadows White Point/Black Point Vibrance Saturation Clarity Vignette Sharpness Tips Have Two Camera Apps On Your Phone Camera App Configurations For Photography Canon 5D Mk III + Canon 2470 f/2.8 v2</description></item><item><title>4-EP</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/4ep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/4ep/</guid><description>Old pipe,
Happens in barrels.</description></item><item><title>4-MMP</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/4mmp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/4mmp/</guid><description>Cassis, passion fruit,
Common Cabernet Sauvignon, Sauvignon Blanc, Cabernet Franc, specially in more ripe harvests.</description></item><item><title>acetaldehyde</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/acetaldehyde/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/acetaldehyde/</guid><description>Musty, moldy
Present in pretty much all wines.</description></item><item><title>Activate Lost Mode</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/activate-lost-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/activate-lost-mode/</guid><description>Se você for assaltado e forçado a entregar o PIN que desbloqueia o seu iPhone, você deve:
Bloquear o seu iPhone pelo iCloud Entrar no icloud.com; entrar na sessão &amp;ldquo;Find iPhone&amp;rdquo;'; selecionar o seu dispositivo roubado colocar no modo &amp;ldquo;Lost Mode&amp;rdquo; Bloquear o seu cartão SIM pela operadora Ligar para sua operadora (ou entrar na área de cliente do site); pedir bloqueio do chip (pelo IMEI) ou da linha (pelo número) Esses dois passos devem ser feitos o mais rápido possível pois com seu celular desbloqueado, o ladrão terá acesso ao seus e-mails, SMS e WhatsApp.</description></item><item><title>Afonso Annes Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/afonso-annes-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/afonso-annes-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Domingos Gonçalves Villas Boas
Morreu em Africa (possivelmente nalguma das campanhas militares da 2.a Dinastia).</description></item><item><title>After Apple-Picking</title><link>https://victor.villas/gardener/after-applepicking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/gardener/after-applepicking/</guid><description>by Robert Frost
My long two-pointed ladder&amp;rsquo;s sticking through a tree
Toward heaven still,
And there&amp;rsquo;s a barrel that I didn&amp;rsquo;t fill
Beside it, and there may be two or three
Apples I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick upon some bough.
But I am done with apple-picking now.
Essence of winter sleep is on the night,
The scent of apples: I am drowsing off.
I cannot rub the strangeness from my sight
I got from looking through a pane of glass</description></item><item><title>Answering the Wrong Questions</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/answering-the-wrong-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/answering-the-wrong-questions/</guid><description>Why does everyone makes more than I do?
Comparing yourself with other people is dangerous. It&amp;rsquo;s hardly productive so say that comparisons shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be done because it&amp;rsquo;s practically impossible to resist. But at the very least, the comparison should be sound and precise such that no wrong conclusions could be made. A good starting point is to sieve through a the initial population of the sample to make sure that these are all individuals to which comparison is not absurd.</description></item><item><title>Aperture</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/aperture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/aperture/</guid><description>The aperture is the opening that allows light into the camera. A wider or narrower opening changes the amount (and direction diversity) of light that comes through during the time the shutter is open.
Apertures are usually described by an f-number: the ratio of the system&amp;rsquo;s Focal Length to the diameter of the aperture. This means that a f/4 aperture is bigger than a f/8 aperture, in fact twice as big in diameter.</description></item><item><title>Aphorism</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/aphorism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/aphorism/</guid><description>An aphorism is a concise, terse, laconic, or memorable expression of a general truth or principle. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful tool for meditation and serves as easy reminders for important lessons or aspirations that could use a bit more attention.
Examples:
Listen To The Sound Of Silence There&amp;rsquo;s A Language Without Question Marks TBD Title - Be Serious when Surprised TBD Title - Assume Nothing</description></item><item><title>Bach's Coffee Cantata</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/bachs-coffee-cantata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/bachs-coffee-cantata/</guid><description>Schweigt stille, plaudert nicht (Be still, stop chattering), also known as the Coffee Cantata, is a secular cantata by Johann Sebastian Bach, composed probably between 1732 and 1735. Although classified as a cantata, it is essentially a miniature comic opera. In a satirical commentary, the cantata amusingly tells of a woman&amp;rsquo;s dependence on coffee.
BWV 211-212 in Apple Music (lyrics)
The work lampoons both the wild popularity of coffee in 18th century Leipzig, as well as the mildly sanctimonious belief held by some of Leipzig society at the time that coffee drinking was a bad habit that needed to be broken.</description></item><item><title>Backpack Checklist</title><link>https://victor.villas/explorer/backpack-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/explorer/backpack-checklist/</guid><description>Hygiene
towel (in a bag)
shampoo
soap
deodorant
perfume
toothbrush
toothpaste
mouthwash
dental floss
Eletronics
cellphone + charger
notebook + charger
portable bateries
earphones
thumbdrive
Clothes
shirts (1 u/day)
shorts (1 u/week)
pants (1 u/week)
boxers (1 u/day)
pajamas (1 u/week)
shoes
socks (1 u/day)
sandals (in a bag)
Utilities
condoms
adapters
Car Extras
charging plug
water bottle
cereal bars
driver&amp;rsquo;s license
car documents
Plane Extras
passport
native currency
Pre-Flight</description></item><item><title>Bacteria vs Heat</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/bacteria-vs-heat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/bacteria-vs-heat/</guid><description>Most bacteria begin to die at 52°C, though it can take upward of 2 hours to safely sterilize food at this temperature.
After about 3 minutes at 64°C, bacteria experience a 7 log reduction - which means that only 1 bacteria will remain for every $10^7$ (million) that were initially there.
At 80°C bacteria experience a 7 log reduction within 1 second.</description></item><item><title>Bean Blends</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</guid><description>Most of commercially available ground coffees are blends of multiple Coffee Beans, as opposed to Single Origin Beans coffee which includes only coffee beans coming from the same location.
Regular coffee are usually blends because the beans used aren&amp;rsquo;t really high grade and are not thoroughly tracked. Specialty Coffee blends on the other hand are an art form on their own.
A good blend recipe has to combine multiple beans in a complementary way, achieving a flavor combination that no Single Origin Beans coffee could.</description></item><item><title>Bellroy Tech Kit</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/bellroy-tech-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/bellroy-tech-kit/</guid><description>https://bellroy.com/products/tech-kit/looma_viroblock_standard/basalt#slide-0
https://bellroy.com/promotions/2021/youtube?promotional-campaign=daniel-titchener-hjsdb-sdhje</description></item><item><title>Blade Grip &amp; Claw</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/blade-grip--claw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/blade-grip--claw/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Brew Strength</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</guid><description>The strength of a coffee brew level is a measure of how noticeable is the flavor in the resulting beverage. Pretty simply, it describes how much of the stuff in the cup is not water. This is why strength is a property of a brew, not a quality determined by the beans.
Strength is directly quantified by the concentration of coffee extract present in the solution. A very diluted coffee is &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; or watery, while a highly concentrated coffee is said to be &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Brewing Control Chart</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</guid><description>The brewing control chart represents brewed coffee flavor profiles as regions on a chart of Brew Strength and Extraction Yield. The chart is divided into nine regions based on specified lower and upper limits for each variable. The vertical axis corresponds to Brew Strength measured in total dissolved solids (TDS) and Extraction Yield measured in mass concentration of dissolved coffee solids. These two specifications overlap to produce a box in the centre of the chart that indicates the most desirable cup of filter coffee.</description></item><item><title>Built-In Waste Bins</title><link>https://victor.villas/decorator/builtin-waste-bins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/decorator/builtin-waste-bins/</guid><description>SORT &amp;amp; GO BUILT-IN BIN by Brabantia https://www.brabantia.com/uk/sort-go-built-in-bin-2-x-16-litre-jade-green-grey/</description></item><item><title>Camera App Configurations For Photography</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-app-configurations-for-photography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-app-configurations-for-photography/</guid><description>These settings are based on the Halide app, but most apps have similar options available.
Let the Grid ON by default to help you with the Rule of Thirds and leveling Let the Exposure Histogram ON by default to help preventing a skewed exposure Let Auto Focus ON in the Focus Ring because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Set Raw+ as the capture mode to save Raw for editing and HEIC for quick sharing Let Coverage OFF to speed up capture as default HEIC is usually good enough Let Auto White Balance ON because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Let Auto Exposure ON by default because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Let Zebras ON to help detect color Clipping due to skewed exposure</description></item><item><title>Camera ISO</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-iso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-iso/</guid><description>ISO controls the sensitivity of the camera. This means that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t control the amount of light entering the camera, but how the camera should interpret the light coming in.
A higher ISO means higher sensitivity, therefore a brighter image for the same amount of light captured. It&amp;rsquo;s useful to raise the ISO when there&amp;rsquo;s no other way to increase brightness (e.g. a slower shutter would add blur and wider aperture would decrease depth of field).</description></item><item><title>Carbon Steel Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/carbon-steel-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/carbon-steel-maintenance/</guid><description>#TODO
“Just like a good cast-iron pan, a carbon steel wok’s performance will improve the more you use it. Most come with a protective film of oil to prevent them from rusting or tarnishing in the store. It’s important to remove this layer before using it the first time. Scrub the wok out with hot soapy water, dry it carefully, and place it over a burner at the highest heat possible until it starts to smoke.</description></item><item><title>Cast-Iron Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/castiron-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/castiron-maintenance/</guid><description>#TODO
“When you first get a cast-iron pan, it will have either a bullet-gray dull finish (if it’s an unseasoned pan) or a slick-looking black surface (a preseasoned pan). Unless you bought a seventy-five-year-old pan at a garage sale, it will also have a pebbly-looking surface, like this:Modern cast iron is bumpy like that because it is not polished the way old cast iron was and retains some texture from the mold.</description></item><item><title>Chaves</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/chaves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/chaves/</guid><description>História e Brasão Sobre a história e o brasão da família Chaves é um pouco mais difícil de encontrar informações, um dos motivos sendo a confusão com o ainda existente município de Chaves em Portugal. Parece ter sido um sobrenome toponímico (referenciando a origem geográfica do indivíduo), o que explicaria ele ser tão comum e não haver uma genealogia unificada.
Considerando que a etimologia do nome da cidade de Chaves tem mais a ver com a dinastia romana Flavius e que em latim referencia uma cor de cabelo amarelo-durado-marrom[7], utilizar objetos chaves (mesmo que na cor dourada) é um acidente linguístico.</description></item><item><title>Choosing a Running Shoe</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/choosing-a-running-shoe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/choosing-a-running-shoe/</guid><description>Five big factors to consider:
Terrain Cushioning Gait Support Size Mileage Terrain Road-running shoes are generally light, flexible and even cushioning with flatter and smoother soles.
Trail-running shoes have bigger lugs to grip on unstable terrain, stronger underfoot and generally stiffer to handle uneven surfaces.
Cross-training shoes are thiner and simpler, to be used indoors for workouts and balance activities.
Cushioning The two main aspects are firmness and thickness of the foam between your feet and the ground.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</guid><description>Coffee Beans come from cherries which grow on the coffee plant.
There are two main plant species of coffee used for consumption: Arabica (Coffea arabica) and Canephora (Coffea canephora). The Canephora species has a most famous variety named Robusta, commonly used as metonym for the species. Robusta is also known as Conilon in Brazil.
The Canephora species is considered to be an ancestor to the Arabica species, but there&amp;rsquo;s also evidence that the better flavor from Arabica was inherited from the Eugenioides species (Coffea eugenioides).</description></item><item><title>Coffee Culture</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-culture/</guid><description>Coffee In the Arts
Bach&amp;rsquo;s Coffee Cantata London&amp;rsquo;s 1674 Petition Against Coffee Sources Eighteenth-Century Coffee-House Culture Edited by Markman Ellis, this four-volume set reprints facsimile satires, plays and histories of the period: Restoration Satire, The Eighteenth-Century Satire, Drama, Science and History Writings. A great resource for archivists and researchers.
The Coffee House: A Cultural History Another book by Markman Ellis, more friendly to coffee lovers and the general public but still well researched and scholarly enough to be a good read for historians - still focused on 18th century England.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Extract</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</guid><description>Roasted coffee is made up of some soluble solids and mostly insoluble solids (mainly cellulose) as well as volatiles that are liberated as gases. The composition depends on the species and variety of the Coffee Beans, the Coffee Fruit Processing, the Roasting and Extraction Methods used.
The soluble solids that are dissolved contribute the most to the brew taste and strength. The volatile soluble compounds contribute to its aroma. Caffeine in particular is among the most soluble components of ground coffee and is extracted early in the process.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Fruit Processing</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</guid><description>The coffee fruit/cherry can be subdivided in:
The seed Bean (endosperm) Silver Skin (spermoderm) Parchment (endocarp) Pulp (mesocarp) Skin (exocarp) The term processing in specialty coffee refers to the methods and preparation used to turn fresh ripe coffee cherries into green beans (which will go through Roasting next). This includes removing the bean from the fruit/cherry (depulping), fermenting and drying the beans. This can be done in several different styles, the 3 most common methods being Natural, Washing and Honey processing and they have a big impact on the final flavor of the coffee.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Grading</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-grading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-grading/</guid><description>Roasted Bean Grading ABIC&amp;rsquo;s PQC Categories #TODO
Tradicional: At least 70% arabica, no more than 20% PVA defects. Superior: At least 85% arabica, no more than 10% PVA defects. Gourmet/Premium: 100% arabica, 0% of PVA defects.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a sustainability certification add-on, requiring at least 60% must be sourced from certified sustainable sources.
BSCA Certification #TODO
Green Bean Grading When buying green beans to be roasted, #TODO
SCA&amp;rsquo;s Green Coffee Grading Protocol The SCA defines a Green Arabica Coffee Classification System (GACCS) based on counting defects on a 350 g sample of beans.</description></item><item><title>Com Que Roupa?</title><link>https://victor.villas/sambista/com-que-roupa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sambista/com-que-roupa/</guid><description>1929 Noel Rosa e sua Turma da Vila
Noel ri da própria desgraça na canção &amp;ldquo;Com que Roupa&amp;rdquo;, gravado em 1930, na qual lamenta: &amp;ldquo;Mesmo eu sendo um cabra trapaceiro, não consigo nem ter pra gastar&amp;rdquo;. Segundo a dupla de biógrafos de Noel Rosa, à época da composição da música coexistiam dois tipos de samba na cidade. Um deles misturava &amp;ldquo;intelectuais e macumbeiros, funcionários públicos e boêmios, pequenos comerciantes bem-sucedidos e operários modestos, ex-escravos e músicos&amp;rdquo;, como Sinhô e Pixinguinha.</description></item><item><title>Combine Comfort With Effort</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/combine-comfort-with-effort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/combine-comfort-with-effort/</guid><description>Because Corresponding Affection Can Be Hard, it&amp;rsquo;s important to guarantee that an attempt will be made. In this case, one way to segue into an affection demonstration with a decreased risk of last-minute second thoughts is to plan ahead an easy start.
For example, for someone that finds hard to initiate with verbal affirmation or physical intimacy, waking up early and making breakfast will get things in motion. The other person will initiate a &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo; or a hug that to be corresponded.</description></item><item><title>Conversa de Botequim</title><link>https://victor.villas/sambista/conversa-de-botequim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sambista/conversa-de-botequim/</guid><description>1935 Noel Rosa
A canção registrada em 1935 foi feita com o compositor e arranjador paulista Vadico, considerado o maior parceiro de Noel. Em Noel Rosa, uma Biografia (1990), os autores João Máximo e Carlos Didier descrevem a canção como uma &amp;ldquo;prodigiosa crônica dos cafés cariocas e seus folgados frequentadores&amp;rdquo;, cercados de garçons, cinzeiros, palitos, jogo do bicho, futebol e pagamento fiado. Para o antropólogo Roberto DaMatta, em artigo no jornal O Globo, os &amp;ldquo;faça o favor&amp;rdquo; espalhados pela letra representam um marcador cultural que torna o pedido algo &amp;ldquo;educado&amp;rdquo;, mesmo que ele seja um imperativo abusivo e absurdo.</description></item><item><title>Corresponding Affection Can Be Hard</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/corresponding-affection-can-be-hard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/corresponding-affection-can-be-hard/</guid><description>Each person might be attuned to demonstrate affection in different ways. For example: verbal affirmation, being present, physical intimacy, gifting, proactive help, respecting space.
Most people will have a few preferred channels to demonstrate affection, which may or may not be their most attuned channel to perceive affection from others. Some people might even be fluent in all of them.
Whatever the case, it can be hard to correspond a demonstration of affection in the same manner if it comes through a channel that is a bit underdeveloped on the receiving side.</description></item><item><title>Create Your Own Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/create-your-own-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/create-your-own-website/</guid><description>Deploying a website into your domain is the foundation for your presence on the Web. Control over its content is what makes it yours, the content itself is what makes it represent you.
There are many ways to create and operate a website: from all-inclusive builders like WordPress, to online hosting a Static Website, to self-hosting a fully-fledged web server.
Simple: Website Builder Platforms Flexible: Free Static Website Hosting A cheap way to operate a website is to use static website hosting, which is often offered freely by several platforms like GitHub, GitLab, Netlify, CloudFlare, DigitalOcean and many others.</description></item><item><title>Cupping</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</guid><description>Coffee Cupping or Coffee Tasting is the practice of observing the taste and aromatics of a Coffee Extract to evaluate its flavor.
It&amp;rsquo;s an industry practice that can be done informally by anyone or with strict protocols and guidelines by professionals. It involves evaluating the coffee after roasting by grinding the beans and steeping it with hot water in cupping bowls for a set amount of time (a very simple and easy to reproduce Immersion Brewing technique).</description></item><item><title>Cutting Tools</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/cutting-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/cutting-tools/</guid><description>Materials Ceramic blades are generally a poor choice. They can be ground to a razor-sharp edge and that that edge doesn’t dull even with prolonged use, but their major drawback is that they chip easily and are unrepairable.
Carbon steel is easy to sharpen and it can be ground down into an extraordinarily sharp edge. Its disadvantages are that it dulls relatively quickly, requiring you to resharpen it every few weeks or so to maintain a good cutting edge; it can rust if not cared for properly; and it will discolor if it comes into prolonged contact with acidic fruits or vegetables.</description></item><item><title>Degassing</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/degassing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/degassing/</guid><description>#TODO https://pubs.acs.org/doi/full/10.1021/acs.jafc.7b03310 #TODO https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2214289422000850 #TODO https://digitalcollection.zhaw.ch/handle/11475/13126</description></item><item><title>Depth of Field</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/depth-of-field/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/depth-of-field/</guid><description>The depth of field is the range of the scene that appears sharp, commonly said to be &amp;ldquo;in Focus&amp;rdquo;. It is determined by the Focal Length and the Aperture diameter.
For landscape photos, the depth of field has to be huge (kilometers). For portrait photos, the depth of field might be just a few centimeters. The ideal depth of field depends on what the subject of the photo is and where/if it&amp;rsquo;s desirable to isolate the rest of the image.</description></item><item><title>Design of a Financial Life in Vancouver</title><link>https://victor.villas/independent/design-of-a-financial-life-in-vancouver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/independent/design-of-a-financial-life-in-vancouver/</guid><description>Banking Credit Cards Credit score is important in Canada - it&amp;rsquo;s factored in for just about everything, from loan interest rates to mobile phone deals and getting ahead when bidding for an apartment. To build up a good credit score, work on a good looking credit history: 1) always pay your credit card in full and on time; 2) open up a line of credit and don&amp;rsquo;t use it. Newcomers will not have the best credit cards available due to lack of credit history, but banks will often have a &amp;ldquo;welcome package&amp;rdquo; for immigrants.</description></item><item><title>diacetyl</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/diacetyl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/diacetyl/</guid><description>Oak, butter, butterscotch, roasted nuts.
Common in Chardonnay and Pinot Noir.</description></item><item><title>Diogo Annes Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/diogo-annes-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/diogo-annes-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Gonçalo Annes Villas Boas children:: Gonçalo Dias Villas Boas
DIOGO married BRITES DE AZEVEDO in 1425.
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 239, $1, N5 : &amp;ldquo;Foi Senhor da Torre e Quinta de Ayró.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Diogo Fernandes de Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/diogo-fernandes-de-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/diogo-fernandes-de-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Fernão Annes de Villas Boas children:: Gonçalo Annes Villas Boas
DIOGO married BRIOLANJA DE ARAÚJO daughter of VASCO RODRIGUES DE ARAÚJO (Filho) in 1375.
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 239, $1, N3 : &amp;ldquo;Foy Sr. da q.ta e Torre de Ayró, e dos Reguengos de Villasboas na Provincia de Traz os Montes, viveo no tempo do Rey D. Pedro 1.o, porem pella demaziada liberdade em q vivia com os moradores das suas terras, o quis o Rey castigar, e auzentando-se por evitar o castigo, deo o dito Rey todos os bens da Croa, e Reguengos, digolhe tirou o dito D.</description></item><item><title>DNS Server</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/dns-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/dns-server/</guid><description>A Domain Name System Server is a piece of Internet infrastructure responsible for translating domain names into to a collection of servers (by their IP addresses) to which requests must be forwarded.
A DNS server might not have the translation available for every domain, so they can communicate with other trusted DNS servers. Domain Registrars usually manage their own DNS servers to allow clients to configure their domains.</description></item><item><title>Domain Registrar</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/domain-registrar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/domain-registrar/</guid><description>A domain name registrar is an organization that manages the reservation of Internet domain names, supervised by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN).
Most registrars will also offer authoritative DNS hosting so their clients can make use of the domain, though this is not implied from the registrar role.
There are several registrars with similarly good prices and user experience: Hover, Gandi.net, Freenom, Porkbun, NameCheap, DNSimle, Google Domains etc.</description></item><item><title>Domingos Gonçalves Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/domingos-gonalves-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/domingos-gonalves-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Gonçalo Dias Villas Boas children:: Gonçalo Domingues Villas Boas, Afonso Annes Villas Boas, Pedro (Villas Boas)
DOMINGOS married ANTÔNIA PEREIRA in 1480.
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 240, $1, N7 : &amp;ldquo;Foi senhor da Torre e q.ta de Ayró&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Dosing Ratios</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/dosing-ratios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/dosing-ratios/</guid><description>Ratios are usually noted as (grams of coffee) to (grams of water), for example 1:16. That&amp;rsquo;s fine if one is usually brewing the mostly the same amount of coffee on every recipe, but a bit backwards if it comes to the situation of figuring out how much coffee to grind to serve some guests. In that case, measuring ratios as (grams of coffee) per (liters of water) is more intuitive and usually results in simpler math.</description></item><item><title>Drink Water</title><link>https://victor.villas/bodybuilder/drink-water/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/bodybuilder/drink-water/</guid><description>https://music.apple.com/br/album/the-water-s/1503803626?l=en</description></item><item><title>Editing on Adobe Lightroom</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/editing-on-adobe-lightroom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/editing-on-adobe-lightroom/</guid><description>Adobe Lightroom is a popular photo editing application, available on smartphones, tablets and desktop.
Light Adjustments The most common task is correcting for white balance.
#TODO What is the tone curve?
Burning and Dodging: make bright brighter and dark darker
Brightness controls the overall look from bright to dark
Contrast (the ratio between highlights and shadows)
Highlights controls the brightness/contrast of the brightest parts of the image
Shadows controls the brightness/contrast of the darkest parts of the image #TODO histogram analysis of highlights vs whites, shadows vs blacks</description></item><item><title>Espresso</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</guid><description>Bean Preparation RDT: Spray or Drop or the Spoon Method Not every grinder has low retention, it&amp;rsquo;s important to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re getting out what you put in.
Puck Preparation Make sure the puck is absolutely dry. Dosing funnel helps with distribution as well.
Distribution. The objective is to have an homogeneous and even bed of coffee to avoid uneven flow. To remove the clumps, use a needled tool to stir and move around the coffee inside.</description></item><item><title>Every Set of Weight Training Should Reach Muscle Failure</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/every-set-of-weight-training-should-reach-muscle-failure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/every-set-of-weight-training-should-reach-muscle-failure/</guid><description>Every set of exercise has a target range of repetitions. For example, a 3 x 8-12 or simply a 3 x 10 set - the standard set for muscle growth because Hypertrophy is Optimal at 8-12 Repetitions.
These sets should use a moderate weight (around 75% of the 1-rep maximum) such that you reach muscle failure - meaning you couldn&amp;rsquo;t execute another repetition no matter how much you wanted it.</description></item><item><title>Exposure</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/exposure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/exposure/</guid><description>Camera exposure controls the amount of light (per unit area) received by the camera, affecting the image brightness.
The luminous exposure is controlled by two settings: Shutter Speed and Aperture. Changing the Camera ISO also affects the brightness of photos and some apps might tinker with it when adjusting exposure, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t technically change the amount of light that enters the camera - just the sensitivity of the sensors inside the camera.</description></item><item><title>Extraction Methods</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1</description></item><item><title>Extraction Yield</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</guid><description>The Extraction Yield, plotted on the horizontal axis, is considered the key measure of coffee flavor.
It is the percentage of the dry coffee bed mass extracted into the beverage.
$$ \frac{\mbox{Yield} \times \mbox{TDS}}{\mbox{Dose}} = \mbox{Extraction Yield} $$ Where the $\mbox{Dose}$ means the weight of coffee used in the recipe, $\mbox{Yield}$ is the total weight of the coffee produced and $\mbox{TDS}$ is the concentration of dissolved solids.
#TODO expand #TODO https://awasteof.</description></item><item><title>F-number Equivalence</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/fnumber-equivalence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/fnumber-equivalence/</guid><description>Given a lens described by an f-number, its effect on Exposure is the same no matter the sensor size of the camera. That&amp;rsquo;s why f-number is useful in the first place: to reduce the Focal Length and Aperture diameter combination into a single variable that completely describes the lens influence on Exposure.
However, different sensor sizes will play a role on the Depth of Field. After adjusting for Focal Length Equivalence (choosing a focal length that yields equivalent framing and perspective), the depth of field is then determined by the Aperture diameter.</description></item><item><title>Fernão Annes de Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/ferno-annes-de-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/ferno-annes-de-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: João Annes de Villas Boas children:: Diogo Fernandes de Villas Boas
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 239, $1, N2: &amp;ldquo;foi Sr. Da Torre e qt.a de Villasboas em Ayró, Sollar desta Famillia como o deixo dito, e dos Reguengos de Villas Boas, Vassalo do Rey D. Deniz.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Financial Independence</title><link>https://victor.villas/independent/financial-independence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/independent/financial-independence/</guid><description>Financial Independence means that money should not get in the way of reasonable quality of life decisions.
This is a naturally vague definition because it requires a bit of common sense and a moving target for one&amp;rsquo;s standards of living.
At the very least, it should include the possibility of giving up income for a few years (making it possible to exchange professions) or completely retiring if expenditures are considerably reduced.</description></item><item><title>Fines Migration</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</guid><description>Using filter paper
https://www.baristahustle.com/blog/fines-migration/
#TODO cite M Petracco, 2005. Percolation. In: A Illy and R Viana (Eds), Espresso Coffee: The Science of Quality, second edition (pp 259-287)</description></item><item><title>Focal Length</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length/</guid><description>In technical terms, the focal point is the geometric place where parallel light rays converge after passing through a lens. In photography, the focal point stays at a small distance from the camera sensors called focal length.
A longer focal length means that light rays coming from objects far away will converge way before reaching the sensors, so they will disperse and the object will appear more blurry. Conversely, light rays coming from objects very near the camera will tend to converge further behind the sensors and will appear more blurry as well.</description></item><item><title>Focal Length Equivalence</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length-equivalence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length-equivalence/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Focus</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focus/</guid><description>An object is said to be focused when its image appears &amp;ldquo;sharp&amp;rdquo;, meaning its edges are clearly defined.
To adjust an image focus is to determine the placement of objects in relation to the Depth of Field. Objects inside this region will appear sharp because the light rays reflected by these objects will converge to a point close to the camera sensors.</description></item><item><title>Focus Mode Persistence</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/focus-mode-persistence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/focus-mode-persistence/</guid><description>As of June 2022, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to query the currently active Focus Mode.
A strategy to achieve similar functionality is to add Shortcut Automations for every Focus Mode such that:
A file in iCloud contains the name of the currently active Focus Mode Whenever a Focus Mode mode is activated, its name is written to the file Whenever a Focus Mode mode is deactivated, a None is written to the file Shortcuts Set Focus Mode Unset Focus Mode Get Focus Mode Write Variable Shortcut Read Variable Shortcut</description></item><item><title>Geraniol</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/geraniol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/geraniol/</guid><description>Dark flowers.</description></item><item><title>Gonçalo Annes Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-annes-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-annes-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Diogo Fernandes de Villas Boas children:: Diogo Annes Villas Boas
GONÇALO married INÊS (ou Domingas) DE MEIRA in 1400.
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 239, $1, N4 : &amp;ldquo;Foi Sr. da Torre de Ayro, foi Alcaide Mor de Castello de Vide, e viveo no tempo do Rey D. João 1.o q o Armou Cavalleiro p.a entrar na batalha de Aljubarrota onde prometeo seria o pr.</description></item><item><title>Gonçalo Dias Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-dias-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-dias-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Diogo Annes Villas Boas children:: Domingos Gonçalves Villas Boas, Pedro Gonçalves Villas Boas, Leonor dos Anjos
GONÇALO married JOANA MARTINS DA COSTA in 1450.
Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 239, $1, N6 : &amp;ldquo;Foi Senhor da Torre e Quinta de Airó outros fazem f.° de Diogo Fz Villas boas N3 mas como vay seguem a mayor parte e os S.res de Ayró.</description></item><item><title>Gonçalo Domingues Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-domingues-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/gonalo-domingues-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Domingos Gonçalves Villas Boas children:: #TODO
GONÇALO married TERESA PAES DE FARIA.</description></item><item><title>Grape Varieties</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/grape-varieties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/grape-varieties/</guid><description>Wine is usually made with grapes, but they&amp;rsquo;re not like the ones you find in the grocery store. All wine grapes comes from a single species (vitis vinifera) and - compared to other grapes - they are smaller, sweeter, have thicker skins and contain seeds.
There are over 1,300 wine grape varieties used in commercial production, the top 100 of these varieties making up 75% of the world&amp;rsquo;s vineyards. Cabernet Sauvignon is the most planted variety, but other popular examples are Merlot, Tempranillo, Airén, Chardonnay, Syrah, Grenache Noir, Sauvignon Blanc and Pinot Noir.</description></item><item><title>Grinding</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</guid><description>In the grinding of coffee, the particle size distribution is the main concern. Finer particles will be more subject to extraction than bigger particles because they have more surface area per volume. Generally speaking, a good grind is a highly concentrated distribution of particle sizes, meaning uniformity of sizes. Total uniformity is not an absolute goal, however, because some diversity of sizes can be useful: having a bit of fines (a nickname for particles much smaller than the bulk of the distribution, usually smaller than $100 \mu m$ and consisting of mostly of bean skin, i.</description></item><item><title>Half-Kneeling Hip Flexor Stretches</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/halfkneeling-hip-flexor-stretches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/halfkneeling-hip-flexor-stretches/</guid><description>Get down into a half-kneeling position with your front and back knees at about a 90-degree angle. Your stance should be around shoulder-width apart and your pelvis should be facing forward. Squeeze the glute on the back leg and also engage your lower abdominals, trying to tuck the pelvis to flatten out your lower back. You may feel a stretch at the front of your hip on the kneeling side.</description></item><item><title>Halide</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/halide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/halide/</guid><description>Auto Focus Mode In automatic Focus mode, it&amp;rsquo;s still possible to tweak the focus by tapping on the viewfinder. Halide will focus on the objects at that region of the image.
Manual Focus Mode Lower numbers focus on closer objects, higher numbers focus on far away objects.
Use the Focus Loupe as a visual aide to the sharpness of an object in the center of the image. If focusing on multiple objects or an entire section of the scene, the Focus Peaking works as a visual indicator of sharp edges on the image.</description></item><item><title>Have Two Camera Apps On Your Phone</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/have-two-camera-apps-on-your-phone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/have-two-camera-apps-on-your-phone/</guid><description>This is a tip for those who want to take serious photography but not really always. There are several situational configurations on camera apps that stay in place after your last use and it can be a hassle to undo them when you just want to snap a quick photo.
Choose a good alternative camera app (e.g. Halide) to be the one for &amp;ldquo;serious photography&amp;rdquo; and set the usual Camera App Configurations For Photography.</description></item><item><title>Heel to Toe Drop</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/heel-to-toe-drop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/heel-to-toe-drop/</guid><description>Heel-to-toe-drop is the height difference between
tornozelo e o dedão. Essa diferença muda a forma que o pé entra em contato com o chão na pisada. Um drop grande promove uma pisada retropé (rearfoot). Quanto menor o drop, mais o tênis vai estimular uma pisada mediopé (midfoot).
Então para quem tem canelite na parte superior da perna ou lesão no joelho, pode ser mais interessante escolher um tênis com um drop um pouco menor.</description></item><item><title>Hide Notification Previews</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/hide-notification-previews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/hide-notification-previews/</guid><description>This will protect your privacy by not allowing whoever possesses your smartphone to read any messages you receive, transactions, e-mails and so on.</description></item><item><title>Hip Flexors</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/hip-flexors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/hip-flexors/</guid><description>The iliopsoas muscle is the strongest hip flexor group and consists of two muscles – the iliacus muscle and the psoas muscle. These muscles are separate in the abdomen but joins in the femur at the lesser trochanter.
The rectus femoris muscle is one of four quadriceps muscles, but is the only one of that muscle group that crosses the hip joint and acts as a hip flexor (as well as knee extensor).</description></item><item><title>História do Samba</title><link>https://victor.villas/sambista/histria-do-samba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sambista/histria-do-samba/</guid><description>Reocupação da Praça XI
Conforme a classe média descobre e se une à escola de samba, a prioridade muda de samba de terreiro para samba enredo. Conta-se de delegados que exigiam conteúdo histórico para as escolas de samba. Cartola saiu da mangueira quando percebeu que precisaria mudar seu estilo de composição para se adequar.</description></item><item><title>Hypertrophy is Optimal at 8-12 Repetitions</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/hypertrophy-is-optimal-at-812-repetitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/hypertrophy-is-optimal-at-812-repetitions/</guid><description>1-5 reps primarily develop strength, with more impact on muscle size and none on endurance. 6-12 reps develop a balance of strength, muscle size and endurance. 13-20 reps develop endurance, with some increases to muscle size and limited impact on strength.
Total mechanical tension, which is a key hypertrophy stimulus, can be maximized through moderate relative loads (e.g. 75% of 1RM) and high volume training (e.g. 10 sets of 10 reps) in comparison with high relative loads (e.</description></item><item><title>IndieAuth</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/indieauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/indieauth/</guid><description>IndieAuth is a protocol for Web Sign-In. It&amp;rsquo;s a standard on top of OAuth that defines how to obtain an OAuth 2.0 Bearer Token for an End-User represented solely by an URL.
The protocol inspects your website for metadata that specifies which authentication endpoint you want to use and then proceeds with the OAuth token negotiation with that endpoint.
Supporting IndieAuth in a service means letting users bring their own authentication provider.</description></item><item><title>Internet Domain Name</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/internet-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/internet-domain-name/</guid><description>An Internet Domain Name is a (supposedly) human-readable string that identifies an entity on the Internet, e.g. wikipedia.org.
Every domain is a name under a Top-Level Domain (TLD). For example, the domain johndoe.net is the johndoe name under the net TLD.
The way to own a domain is to purchase it with a Domain Registrar for an annual fee. TLDs and registrars are regulated by IANA/ICANN.
A domain is yours as long as you pay the fees for it and unless you&amp;rsquo;re legally obliged to stop using it due to some drastic reason.</description></item><item><title>iPhone Specific Considerations</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/iphone-specific-considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/iphone-specific-considerations/</guid><description>iPhone cameras lenses do not have movable iris so the Aperture isn&amp;rsquo;t adjustable. Instead, Apple provides different lenses with combinations of Aperture and Focal Length. For example, the iPhone 13 Pro has:
Ultra wide Lens -&amp;gt; 13 mm focal length, f/1.8 aperture Wide Lens -&amp;gt; 26 mm focal length, f/1.5 aperture Telephoto Lens -&amp;gt; 77 mm focal length, f/2.8 aperture #TODO https://www.dpreview.com/articles/6780391159/all-apple-iphone-13-and-13-pro-camera-upgrades-explained #TODO https://www.dpreview.com/articles/2666934640/what-is-equivalence-and-why-should-i-care
Portrait Mode works better with the 2x lens and it allows the adjustment of f-stop.</description></item><item><title>isoamyl acetate</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/isoamyl-acetate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/isoamyl-acetate/</guid><description>Vinegar, bananas.
Common in commercial wines fermented in low temperatures to be more fruity.</description></item><item><title>João Annes de Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/joo-annes-de-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/joo-annes-de-villas-boas/</guid><description>children:: Fernão Annes de Villas Boas
João Annes de Villasboas, o primeiro a usar este apelido. Viveu no século XIII, no reinado dos Reis D. Afonso III e D. Dinis. Ver &amp;ldquo;Nobiliário de Famílias de Portugal&amp;rdquo;, Felgueira Gayo, VOL. 28, Título Villasboas, pág 238, $1, N1 : &amp;ldquo;o primeiro deste appellido de q temos notisia, descendente emqt.o a nós de hum dos dois Irmãos Florerntinos de q he comua openião, e por isso Sr.</description></item><item><title>Joint Mobility Work Is Required Daily</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/joint-mobility-work-is-required-daily/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/joint-mobility-work-is-required-daily/</guid><description>Joint mobility work is necessary and should be done every morning. If you have a popping or creaking joint, double the work. If it is painful, move slower, consult with a professional and - with his consent - triple the work.
Because Every Set of Weight Training Should Reach Muscle Failure, joints are under a lot of stress during weight training. It is good to warm up before workouts, but it&amp;rsquo;s also good to do mobility work as a totally separate (earlier) session.</description></item><item><title>Latte Art</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/latte-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/latte-art/</guid><description>Spout Proximity The further up you are, the more swaying and swirling happens, blurring the design.
Starting Point Don&amp;rsquo;t start in the center, start higher. The more drops necessary, the deeper the start can be because the ripples will move around.
Pushing Forward Move backward as little as possible, only necessary if the design requires it.</description></item><item><title>Leonor dos Anjos</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/leonor-dos-anjos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/leonor-dos-anjos/</guid><description>parents:: Gonçalo Dias Villas Boas
Conforme Felgueria Gayo : &amp;ldquo;Freira Clarissa no Mosteiro de Santa Clara de Vila do Conde.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Lever Espresso Maker</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/lever-espresso-maker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/lever-espresso-maker/</guid><description>Flair 58 https://flairespresso.com/product/flair-58/
Accessories https://www.naked-portafilter.com/smart-espresso-profiler/</description></item><item><title>Life Is All About Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/life-is-all-about-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/life-is-all-about-maintenance/</guid><description>Life is all about maintenance. Your body, your house, your relationships; everything requires constant and never-ending maintenance.</description></item><item><title>Lighting</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/lighting/</guid><description>There are 3 main aspects to consider in a light source: the color, the strength, and the direction.
The color of the light source refers to the specific color spectrum. Natural sunlight has a very different spectrum than fluorescent white lamps. Natural light tends to produce great photos for many reasons, one of them is that it&amp;rsquo;s a spectrum of light that we are used to appreciate; it feels natural. Of course, this varies with Sun&amp;rsquo;s position and local weather: the mid-day sun is &amp;ldquo;cooler&amp;rdquo; (more blue), specially when it&amp;rsquo;s cloudy, but sunrise and sunset are very &amp;ldquo;warm&amp;rdquo; (more red).</description></item><item><title>Listen To The Sound Of Silence</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/listen-to-the-sound-of-silence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/listen-to-the-sound-of-silence/</guid><description>An Aphorism conveying the importance of active listening and achieving empathy.
Interpretation Hold talking, keep listening. Give some time for words to be processed into meaning.
Wait for silence, let it be, &amp;ldquo;listen&amp;rdquo; to it (meaning, evaluate it) as much as you were listening to the spoken words before.
What kind of silence is it? Is it a post-rant silence? A help-seeking silence? A comfort-needing silence? Listen to how that silence sounds.</description></item><item><title>London's 1674 Petition Against Coffee</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/londons-1674-petition-against-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/londons-1674-petition-against-coffee/</guid><description>The Women&amp;rsquo;s Petition Against Coffee, Representing to Public Consideration the Grand INCONVENIENCES accruing to their SEX from the Excessive Use of that Drying, Enfeebling LIQUOR, Presented to the Right Honorable the Keepers of the Liberty of VENUS, by a Well-willer. London, Printed 1674.
The petition protested against the consumption of coffee arguing that it made men sterile and impotent and stated that it contributed to the nation&amp;rsquo;s failing birth rate. According to the petition, coffee made men &amp;ldquo;as unfruitful as the sandy deserts, from where that unhappy berry is said to be brought.</description></item><item><title>Luxury Allowance</title><link>https://victor.villas/independent/luxury-allowance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/independent/luxury-allowance/</guid><description>Orçamento Um esquema orçamentário que permite calibrar as expectativas de quais serviços e bens são compatíveis com uma renda passiva hipotética.
Premissas:
Câmbio: 1 USD → 6 BRL Juros: 4% a.a. → 0,33% a.m. Cronograma:
Celular (4 anos) → 2023, 2027, 2031, &amp;hellip; Tablete (4 anos) → 2024, 2028, 2032, &amp;hellip; Relógio (4 anos) → 2025, 2029, 2033, &amp;hellip; Computador (6 anos) → 2022, 2028, 2034 &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Maillard Reaction</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/maillard-reaction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/maillard-reaction/</guid><description>#TODO Maillard browning reactions</description></item><item><title>Man With a Hoe</title><link>https://victor.villas/gardener/man-with-a-hoe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/gardener/man-with-a-hoe/</guid><description>The Man with the Hoe &amp;ldquo;The Man with the Hoe&amp;rdquo; is a poem by the American poet Edwin Markham, inspired by Jean-François Millet&amp;rsquo;s painting L&amp;rsquo;homme à la houe, a painting interpreted as a socialist protest about the peasant&amp;rsquo;s plight.
Excerpt:
Bowed by the weight of centuries he leans
Upon his hoe and gazes on the ground,
The emptiness of ages in his face,
And on his back the burden of the world.</description></item><item><title>Matching Iphone wallpapers to modular watch face color gradients</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/matching-iphone-wallpapers-to-modular-watch-face-color-gradients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/matching-iphone-wallpapers-to-modular-watch-face-color-gradients/</guid><description>This is surprisingly hard. It&amp;rsquo;s already hard to get an accurate capture of the watch face colors. For some reason if you take a screen capture on your watch the colors will not perfectly match what your eyes are seeing on the device display - perhaps color calibration or brightness effects?
If you have any knowledge on this or would like to suggest a correction, please reach out. The only way I found to go through this is by using the color picker on watch face previews and then eye-balling a correction to brightness and tones so it will look as I wanted.</description></item><item><title>Meetup Tracking</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/meetup-tracking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/meetup-tracking/</guid><description>The contact evaluation metric considers three aspects: availability, friendliness, and initiative. Each aspect is graded in the set {1, 2, 3, 4} according to the following criteria:
Availability Requires week-long planning or more Requires up to a day or two of planning Planning preferred but doable by end of day Could happen almost any time without notice Friendliness Some topics are preferably avoided Conversations are relaxed by default Frequently one loses track of time Tempting to keep going for an all-nighter Initiative Rarely initiates a conversation Sometimes initiates a conversation Frequently hits up for a chat or a meet Invites for all sorts of activities</description></item><item><title>Methoxipyrazines</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/methoxipyrazines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/methoxipyrazines/</guid><description>Herbaceous, green notes, grass, bell pepper, green pepper.
Common in Sauvignon Blanc and Cabernet Sauvignon, specially in less-ripe harvests.</description></item><item><title>MINIX 3-Port Wall Charger</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/minix-3port-wall-charger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/minix-3port-wall-charger/</guid><description>https://www.amazon.co.uk/MINIX-Charger-Charging-Adapter-Compatible/dp/B08M3L8BFT/ref=sr_1_5?crid=2YXG0UUEZ9JU9&amp;keywords=minix+charger&amp;qid=1645982352&amp;sprefix=minix+charger%2Caps%2C85&amp;sr=8-5</description></item><item><title>Moka</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</guid><description>#TODO translate
Cafeteira Italiana (Moka) A cafeteira italiana é um dos métodos mais tradicionais e democráticos de se fazer café. Uma vez descoberta a &amp;ldquo;receita&amp;rdquo; ideal para sua cafeteira e café escolhidos, ela é fácil e consistente. Com ela, é possível trazer um café muito semelhante a um espresso para dentro de casa.
Procedimento No entanto, para quem ainda não encontrou a receita ideal ela pode ser um pouco difícil de domar.</description></item><item><title>Morning Skin Care</title><link>https://victor.villas/bodybuilder/morning-skin-care/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/bodybuilder/morning-skin-care/</guid><description>#TODO
https://www.sallve.com.br/blogs/sallve/planner-da-sallve-para-organizar-a-rotina-de-skincare https://www.sallve.com.br/blogs/sallve/dia-ou-noite-em-que-hora-do-dia-e-melhor-aplicar-seus-cosmeticos https://www.sallve.com.br/blogs/sallve/skincare-para-preguicosos https://www.sallve.com.br/blogs/sallve/pele-oleosa-rotina-de-skincare https://www.sallve.com.br/blogs/sallve/afinal-de-contas-qual-e-a-ordem-certa-da-sua-rotina-de-skincare
Gothamista https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v71J0sTjvXI https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Es8Fa9JcY1A Cleanse Vitamin C Hydration Moisturizer Sunscreen Lips
Hyram https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XzVNVyb5Af0
Cleanse Hair Care Serum Eye Cream Moisturizer Sunscreen</description></item><item><title>No-Bypass Filter Brew</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a concept around pour-over coffee.
Some of the water goes side-ways in the filter and around the coffee. That water is called bypass water.
The more water goes through coffee, the more solubles down the cup. Less bypass means more effective and efficient extraction. A stronger extraction.
Aeropress is zero-bypass, espresso as well. But water doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through coffee, it takes pressure.
Models: Tricolate Next Level</description></item><item><title>Noel Rosa</title><link>https://victor.villas/sambista/noel-rosa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sambista/noel-rosa/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Office Chair</title><link>https://victor.villas/decorator/office-chair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/decorator/office-chair/</guid><description>https://www.hermanmiller.com/en_br/products/seating/side-chairs/setu-chair/
A clear, half-height and semi-transparent chair helps not filling too much visual space.</description></item><item><title>Own Your Internet Domain Name</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/own-your-internet-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/own-your-internet-domain-name/</guid><description>Having your own personal Internet Domain Name is the first step towards building an identity and setting up your own corner of the Web. A domain costs money, but a cheap one costs as much as a telephone number.
Because the domain serves as a foundation to your online identity, it should be chosen carefully and considered permanent as much as possible. There are a few tools like CunningBot that can help you choose your domain name and others like Instant Domain Search that can quickly search under which TLDs that name is available.</description></item><item><title>Pans &amp; Pots</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/pans--pots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/pans--pots/</guid><description>Materials Stainless steel is durable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require too much maintenance, but it also is an extremely poor heat conductor. What this means is that heat will not travel rapidly through it. Stainless steel pans tend to develop distinct hot and cold spots that match the heat pattern of your burners. This can lead to uneven cooking, resulting in, for example, an omelet that’s burned in some spots and still raw in others.</description></item><item><title>Pedro (Villas Boas)</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/pedro-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/pedro-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Domingos Gonçalves Villas Boas
Frade Dominicano (da Ordem dos Pregadores de s. Domingos)</description></item><item><title>Pedro Gonçalves Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/pedro-gonalves-villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/people/pedro-gonalves-villas-boas/</guid><description>parents:: Gonçalo Dias Villas Boas
Segundo Felgueira Gayo : &amp;ldquo;Abade da Igreja de Santa Comba de Crujães (freguesia contigua a S. Jorge de Airó, onde se acha o Paço de Airó e hoje anexada a S. Bento da Várzea).&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Peg Board</title><link>https://victor.villas/decorator/peg-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/decorator/peg-board/</guid><description>IKEA SKADIS</description></item><item><title>Personal Knowledge Database</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/personal-knowledge-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/personal-knowledge-database/</guid><description>A personal knowledge database (PKB) is a collection of interlinked notes with no particular schema.</description></item><item><title>Portifolio Returns</title><link>https://victor.villas/independent/portifolio-returns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/independent/portifolio-returns/</guid><description>Assumptions $X$ currency/year initial net income $R_I$% net income raise every year $R_F$% yearly near risk-free real return $R_M$% yearly market real return Saving $S$% of net income $A_F$% of savings invested on risk-free $A_M$% of savings invested on market Theoretical Performance The total wealth $W$ after $n$ years available at year $n+1$ can be recursively defined by: $$ W_{n+1} = W_n(1 + A_F R_F + A_M R_M) + SX(1+R_I)^n $$ Solving the recursion using $W_0 = 0$, we get: $$ W_n = \frac{ SX((1 + A_F R_F + A_M R_M)^n_-(1+R_I)^n) }{ A_F R_F + A_M R_M - R_I } $$</description></item><item><title>Portrait Editing Technique</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/portrait-editing-technique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/portrait-editing-technique/</guid><description>Portraits are good opportunities to use a shallow Depth of Field, having the focus solely on the main subject. If the photo wasn&amp;rsquo;t taken in such way, a good place to start is to mask the background and add a bit of blur. #TODO how?
Starting with lighting. Portraits usually start with a bright subject, so the idea is to further contrast it with the surroundings. This can be done with a small bump up in Contrast and Highlights plus a notch down on Shadows.</description></item><item><title>Pour Over</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</guid><description>Bypass It&amp;rsquo;s when water goes around the beans, instead of through. The higher the water level relative to the coffee bed, the more bypass in a regular filter.
See also: No-Bypass Filter Brew
Bloom The main goal of the bloom is to degass (remove CO2) from the coffee grounds. CO2 insulate solubles and also create channeling - which gets in the way of uniform diffusion -, so degassing with as little water as possible contributes to the overall quality of extraction.</description></item><item><title>RelMeAuth</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/relmeauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/relmeauth/</guid><description>RelMeAuth is a protocol for Web Sign-In. This protocol inspects your website for links to other identities of yours that could be used for authentication.
For example, these can be links to your profile on some platform like GitHub or social media like Twitter. If the service confirms such profile belongs to the same person that operates this website, the protocol knows that it can use this service&amp;rsquo;s authentication to confirm your identity.</description></item><item><title>Require Unlock for Control Center</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/require-unlock-for-control-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/require-unlock-for-control-center/</guid><description>Um celular roubado imediatamente colocado em modo avião não vai mais transmitir sua posição ou se comunicar com a Internet, o que impede sua localização e o funcionamento da funcionalidade de &amp;ldquo;Marcar como Perdido&amp;rdquo; ou &amp;ldquo;Apagar Dispositivo&amp;rdquo;. Enquanto isso o assaltante pode usar as funcionalidades offline como ver seus contatos, suas fotos e arquivos locais, seus e-mails baixados anteriormente etc.
Para mitigar esse risco, você pode configurar o seu iPhone para exigir</description></item><item><title>Roasting</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</guid><description>Roasting is the final processing step before the Coffee Beans can be finally consumed, after Coffee Fruit Processing. It plays a major role on the final flavor profile of the Coffee Extract, as though beans will naturally have their different characteristics, their chemical composition is dramatically affected by the roasting process (pyrolysis).
For example, roasting affects the solubility of carbohydrates. Increased degrees of roasting increase the solubility of galactomannans, but too much roasting leads to degradation of arabinogalactans.</description></item><item><title>Runner's Knee</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-knee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-knee/</guid><description>Runner&amp;rsquo;s Knee is an umbrella term for several conditions that can cause discomfort or pain around the knee cap or the patella region.
Any activity that stresses the knee joint can cause.
A dull or aching feeling above, below or behind the knee cap. May experience swelling, cracking, popping or grinding sensation.
Irritation of the soft tissue or lining of the knee, worn or torn cartilage or strained tendons.
How to prevent it?</description></item><item><title>Runner's Loop</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-loop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/runners-loop/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Running Shoe Whishlist</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/running-shoe-whishlist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/running-shoe-whishlist/</guid><description>Experimentar Nike Air Zoom Pegasus 38
Adidas Ultraboost 21
Fila Float Fly: 279
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-fila-float-fly-feminino-953275.html?cor=4P
ASICS Gel nimbus 23
Nike ZoomX Invincible Run
Nike ZoomX Next% 2
Sketchers Go Run Max Road 4
ON Cloudflyer
300 km
600 km / 300 km
900 km / 600 km / 300 km
Reddit
New Balance Rebel V2: 799,99 - 210g - 6mm
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-new-balance-rebel-v2-corrida-masculino-m0irr8-mktp.html?cor=31
New Balance 1080v11: 999,99 - 285g - 8mm
https://www.centauro.com.br/tenis-new-balance-1080v11---masculino-m0il8v-mktp.html?cor=06
https://www.decathlon.com.br/tenis-de-corrida-masculino-1080v11-102000/p</description></item><item><title>Searing Does NOT Seal In Meat Juices</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/searing-does-not-seal-in-meat-juices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/searing-does-not-seal-in-meat-juices/</guid><description>The myth that searing the meat &amp;ldquo;seal in&amp;rdquo; its juices comes from a book by Justus von Liebig in 1847. The idea was that the crust would create a barrier that traps the meat juices inside.
Multiple experiments have shown that this is not the case. Harold McGee said on his 1984 book titled On Food and Cooking: “The crust that forms around the surface of the meat is not waterproof, as any cook has experienced: the continuing sizzle of meat in the pan or oven or on the grill is the sound of moisture continually escaping and vaporizing.</description></item><item><title>Set Up a Web Sign-In Method</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/set-up-a-web-signin-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/set-up-a-web-signin-method/</guid><description>If you already Use a Custom Email Address, a simple method is to use email authentication supported by RelMeAuth.
RelMeAuth might support one of the platforms or social networks you have an account, but consider a bonus independence point not relying on those to authenticate you anywhere.
Additionally, configuring IndieAuth with IndieAuth.com for authorization will allow you to use your email-based RelMeAuth to sign in to websites that don&amp;rsquo;t support RelMeAuth directly but do support the IndieAuth standard.</description></item><item><title>Sharpening</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/sharpening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/sharpening/</guid><description>Most home cooks should sharpen their knives at least twice a year, much more frequently if they use their knives every day.
Use a Sharpening Stone. The best method by far. Not only will it give you the best edge, but it will also remove the least amount of material.
When buying a water stone, look for a large one, at least 2½ inches wide and 8 inches long and an inch thick.</description></item><item><title>Shelves</title><link>https://victor.villas/decorator/shelves/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/decorator/shelves/</guid><description>Product Overview https://www.ikea.com/us/en/cat/kallax-series-27534/
Customization https://www.ikea.com/addon-app/kallax/latest/#/m2/us/en/?
It can have some half-shelves https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/kallax-insert-with-1-shelf-white-20423720/
Boxes can be used for flexible storage https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/kuggis-storage-box-white-60394947/ https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/tjena-storage-box-with-lid-white-40469302/ https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/droena-box-white-00306270/
It can have inserts and drawers https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/kallax-shelf-unit-with-10-inserts-white-s09278338/
Inserts https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/kallax-insert-with-door-white-20278167/
Drawers https://www.ikea.com/us/en/p/kallax-insert-with-2-drawers-white-70286645/</description></item><item><title>Shot Composition</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/shot-composition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/shot-composition/</guid><description>Composition is the art of arranging the objects in the shot with purpose. The subject of the photo should be perceived intuitively, with a guided navigation for the viewers eyes through the important details.
Perspective low angle high angle lateral movement first person POV Vantage Point: points of focus created by leading lines, starting outside the frame and converging inward to a single area of focus Geometric found in objects Organic lines found in nature Rule of Thirds: separate your frame in 9 parts.</description></item><item><title>Shutter Speed</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/shutter-speed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/shutter-speed/</guid><description>Shutter speed controls the amount of time the camera spends taking a picture, that is, absorbing light. This can be a 1/10000 of a second, or an entire hour depending on the camera capabilities. Long times will capture lots of light; short times will capture a little bit of light.
Shutter speed also affects Motion Blur. A moving object will reflect light at multiple locations during the capture interval, reducing image sharpness.</description></item><item><title>Single Origin Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
As opposed to Bean Blends. Common in Specialty Coffee.</description></item><item><title>Single Variety</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/single-variety/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/single-variety/</guid><description>A single-varietal wine is made primarily with just one of the Grape Varieties. It’s common to see these wines labeled by the name of that grape variety. For example, a bottle of Riesling is made with Riesling grapes. It’s useful to note that each country has different rules for how much of the variety should be included to be labeled as a varietal wine.</description></item><item><title>Smartphone Hardening</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/smartphone-hardening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/smartphone-hardening/</guid><description>Threat Level: stolen while locked Use a Passphrase as Lock Screen passcode to reduce the odds of it being guessed and remembered by others Hide Notification Previews in the Lock Screen to prevent others from seeing private content without unlocking Use a SIM card PIN to lock your SIM if transferred to a different device or if the phone is turned off and on again Require Unlock for Control Center to prevent others from turning off GPS or mobile data without turning off the phone Threat Level: stolen while unlocked Trusted Phone Number de outra pessoa iOS Content Restrictions (Screen Time) Use um app de E-mail com senha própria Threat Level: stolen with passcode #TODO time restriction iCloud with password Countermeasures:</description></item><item><title>Social Operating System</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/social-operating-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/social-operating-system/</guid><description>The Social Operating System is a set of processes and tools aiming:
To maintain a healthy social circle as a functioning adult; To prevent important relationships from attention starvation; To filter out relationships not worth the maintenance investment. The processes are:
The periodic Meetup Tracking The tools are:
Documentation Instagram WhatsApp</description></item><item><title>Specialty Coffee</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
For coffee to be labelled as specialty it needs to reach a score of over 80/100 when coffee gets cupped by industry professionals (usually certified graders).
The Brazilian Association of the Coffee Industry (ABIC) introduced a quality rating system based on bean defects:
Tradicional: between 4,5 and 6,0 Superior: between 6 and 7,2 Gourmet: between 7,3 and 10 But it also uses the Especial denomination for Specialty Coffee as defined by the SCA, adopted by the Brazilian Specialty Coffee Association (BSCA).</description></item><item><title>Static Website With Hugo</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/static-website-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/static-website-with-hugo/</guid><description>Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators out there.
Bare Bones Setup Basic Templates Base Layout This is used as starting point for pretty much all other pages and should take care of the most generic boilerplate. The template below includes basic responsiveness configurations and very minimal styling.
layouts/_default/baseof.html
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;#34;{{ .Site.LanguageCode }}&amp;#34; dir=&amp;#34;ltr&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;#34;X-UA-Compatible&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;IE=edge&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;#34;viewport&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;icon&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;{{ &amp;#34;favicon.</description></item><item><title>Stirrup Hoe</title><link>https://victor.villas/gardener/stirrup-hoe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/gardener/stirrup-hoe/</guid><description>“The stirrup hoe, also called the oscillating, Appalachia, or shuffle hoe (buyer beware: several different styles of hoe are called shuffle hoes) has a U-shaped steel blade that swings through a small arc on the end of its too-short wooden handle. In fact, it looks just like a stirrup on a stick. As you draw it toward you, the blade runs under the soil and slices the weed (or whatever else is in its path) several inches below the surface.</description></item><item><title>Storage Solutions</title><link>https://victor.villas/decorator/storage-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/decorator/storage-solutions/</guid><description>IKEA ENUDDEN IKEA TJUSIG
MUJI ALUMINIUM HOOK COMMAND UTENSIL HOOK
JOSEPH JOSEPH PAN LID HOLDER
MUJI PP MAKEUP BOX
KMART Stackable Bamboo Drawers
TARGET Small Stackable Basket
Shelf Inserts!
IKEA SKUBB compartmentalized box
Maidsmart Junk Drawer Organizer
IKEA REJSA Boxes IKEA SKAKARE Boxes IKEA RETRAT Knife Box
IKEA BISSA Shoe Cabinet for the hallways
Muji PP Drawers
IKEA Fredavang underbed drawers IKEA EKBY ALEX floating drawers
IKEA KUNGSFOR hangers IKEA KAMPIG brass hook IKEA TRULSTORP coffee table</description></item><item><title>Sustainability</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/sustainability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/sustainability/</guid><description>#TODO Rainforest Alliance / Utz Certified Cafés Sustentáveis do Brasil (Abic)</description></item><item><title>Sweetness</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</guid><description>Sugar and Sweetness Sweetness is a basic taste most commonly perceived when eating foods rich in certain substances (usually carbohydrates) called sugars. Simple sugars (monosaccharides) include glucose, fructose, and galactose. Compound sugars (disaccharides) are molecules made of two bonded monosaccharides; common examples are sucrose (glucose + fructose), lactose (glucose + galactose), and maltose (two molecules of glucose). Chains of monosaccharides longer than two are not regarded as sugars and are called oligosaccharides or polysaccharides.</description></item><item><title>Tasting</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/tasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/tasting/</guid><description>Within the tiny minutia of wine (the phenols, esters, higher alcohols, acids, etc.), you’ll find the complexities of the wine’s flavors and aroma. Each of the Grape Varieties exhibits these compounds at different levels and many facets explain wine’s unique flavor: acidity, sweetness, alcohol, tannin, and aroma compounds produced in fermentation.
Aroma: Some wines smell like berries, and others smell like flowers. Another contributing factor to wine’s aromas is aging. Nearly all red wines are aged in oak, which contributes an oak barrel’s flavor compounds (like vanillan) and acts as a conduit to expose the wine to oxygen.</description></item><item><title>Tasting And Dialing Exercises</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/tasting-and-dialing-exercises/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/tasting-and-dialing-exercises/</guid><description>Pour Over Salami Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QgYNCTiZKQs&amp;t=473s
Bloom with 25g Pour 75g First stage of extraction. Dissolving the easiest materials. Acids and salts. It&amp;rsquo;s thick, heavy. Where most of the extraction happens.
Thick, dark, aroma. Fidelity on fruity notes, but the salts and acids give a tart and unripe feel. A smooth but sour cup.
Pour 75g ~0:50s Second stage. Simple and complex sugars. Sweetness.
Sweeter but without texture or clarity. Water with cane sugar.</description></item><item><title>TBD Title - Assume Nothing</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/tbd-title--assume-nothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/tbd-title--assume-nothing/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>TBD Title - Be Serious when Surprised</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/tbd-title--be-serious-when-surprised/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/tbd-title--be-serious-when-surprised/</guid><description>#TODO 😊 Serious when surprised Não rir, levar mais a sério / Risível = ridículo</description></item><item><title>TCA</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/tca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/tca/</guid><description>Develops from mold in the corks.</description></item><item><title>The ENCODE Framework</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/the-encode-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/the-encode-framework/</guid><description>A framework for note-taking used in Personal Knowledge Database systems. The acronym stands for Encounter, Note, Connect, Organize, Develop, Express.
That&amp;rsquo;s interesting&amp;hellip; That reminds me of&amp;hellip; That belongs with&amp;hellip; This can be incremented a bit! Do I want more of this?</description></item><item><title>The Fourfold Task</title><link>https://victor.villas/ethicist/the-fourfold-task/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/ethicist/the-fourfold-task/</guid><description>The four observations on Sidarta Gautama&amp;rsquo;s first teachings are usually stated in today&amp;rsquo;s language as:
Existence is suffering The origin of suffering is craving The ceasing of suffering is the ceasing of craving The way to the ceasing of craving is the noble eightfold path This contemplation gives birth to four efforts, phrased in modern terms with Steven Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s lenses(1)(2):
Suffering is to be fully known What arises is to be let go of The ceasing is to be beheld The way is to be cultivated These efforts arouse the Tiantai Bodhisattva vows, phrased using Robert F.</description></item><item><title>There's A Language Without Question Marks</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/theres-a-language-without-question-marks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/theres-a-language-without-question-marks/</guid><description>An Aphorism conveying the parsimony of questioning as a mean to connect instead of probing to dissect.
Interpretation Hold questioning, keep listening. Give some space for words to be processed into meaning.
Words are ambiguous because reality is ambiguous. Analyzing it can be useful, but being useful is not always the most important goal.
What is the big picture? Is there a way to understand this language without getting lost on the river of symbols?</description></item><item><title>Titicaca Lake</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/photos/titicaca-lake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/photos/titicaca-lake/</guid><description>Final Halfway Raw</description></item><item><title>Top-Level Domain</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/toplevel-domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/toplevel-domain/</guid><description>A top-level domain (TLD) is the last part of a domain name, such as .com, .net, .org.
These are regulated by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) but operation is delegated to specific organizations depending on the purpose of the TLD.
An exhaustive list of existing TLDs can be fount at https://www.iana.org/domains/root/db. No every Domain Registrar is licensed to offer every existing TLD.</description></item><item><title>Training Plan - Hero</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--hero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--hero/</guid><description>This is a training plan
1 rest day after Easy Run 2 rest days after Speed Run 2 rest days after Long Run Easy Run Speed Run Long Run 40m easy 50m Fartlek 50m long 30m easy 50m Fartlek 40m long Workout Type Pace Time Recovery Jog 6:48 - 7:19 Long Runs 6:12 - 6:58 Easy Runs 6:10 - 6:43 &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Steady Run 5:47 - 6:02 Tempo Run 5:34 - 5:45 Intervals 5:28 - 5:39 #TODO 25 Minute 5K Guide</description></item><item><title>Training Plan - Walker</title><link>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--walker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/athlete/training-plan--walker/</guid><description>This is a training plan for absolute starters or those recovering from injury. The focus is on getting the joints ready for higher intensity workouts as safely as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s much better to progress slowly and surely than to risk having to start all over again.
#TODO organize
Stretch a lot.
Half-Kneeling Hip Flexor Stretches The glute stretch Lie face up in the floor with knees and hips bent Place your right ankle across your left thigh Grab your left thigh with both hands and pull gently towards chest hold for 20 to 30 seconds and then switch sides</description></item><item><title>Use a Custom Email Address</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/use-a-custom-email-address/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/use-a-custom-email-address/</guid><description>The most immediate advantage of owning a domain is to be able to customize your email address. Not all e-mail providers support this, but even if yours don&amp;rsquo;t you can also try relying on your Domain Registrar to provide an inbox and/or Email forwarding.
Having all your e-mail coming through an address that you own allows you to change providers without the hassle of notifying all your contacts and updating all your credentials.</description></item><item><title>Use a Passphrase</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-passphrase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-passphrase/</guid><description>Instead of simple numeric passcodes or complex random strings mixed with special characters, use a passphrase as your &amp;ldquo;Custom Alphanumeric&amp;rdquo; passcode.
https://www.useapassphrase.com/
You will have to type this password once in a while and this can be a bit annoying, but 99% of the time you&amp;rsquo;ll get by with biometrics so it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it seems.
This is an important passcode and it should be stored in your Password Manager.</description></item><item><title>Use a Password Manager</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-password-manager/</guid><description>Sharing password between different services is bad information security hygiene. You would need to keep track of all the data breaches going on around the world - and when one does inevitably happen, begins the nightmare of updating said password everywhere you&amp;rsquo;ve been using it.
Using variations of a main password doesn&amp;rsquo;t work either. If your variation technique is simple enough to be easy to remember, it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough for a computer to guess.</description></item><item><title>Use a SIM card PIN</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-sim-card-pin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-sim-card-pin/</guid><description>Mesmo que o seu celular seja roubado sem o passcode, é possível pegar o SIM e colocar em outro celular para receber SMS e receber ligações (enquanto você não fizer o bloqueio do chip).
Assim como você pode ter um PIN para o iPhone, é possível escolher um outro PIN específico para o seu cartão SIM. Esse PIN é exigido sempre que o celular tenta estabelecer conectividade com a sua operadora.</description></item><item><title>vanillin</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/vanillin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/vanillin/</guid><description>Vanilla, oak.
Maturation in oak barrels, specially in American barrels.</description></item><item><title>Vapor-Liquid Equilibrium Demonstrator</title><link>https://victor.villas/collector/vaporliquid-equilibrium-demonstrator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/collector/vaporliquid-equilibrium-demonstrator/</guid><description>Hand boilers are used to demonstrate vapor-liquid equilibrium. The colored liquid in the boiler is comprised of a volatile mixture of liquids that have a boiling point close to room temperature.
When someone places their hands in the lower chamber, body heat increases the gas temperature and causes the gas to expand. The heat also causes some liquid to evaporate, which further expands the gas and pushes the liquid upwards.</description></item><item><title>Villas Boas</title><link>https://victor.villas/genealogist/villas-boas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/genealogist/villas-boas/</guid><description>O registro no Nobiliário das Famílias de Portugal por Felgueiras Gaio, especificamente o Tomo XXVIII, páginas 238~239, relata que este é um dos sobrenomes portugueses mais antigos conhecidos pois já nos tempos do Rei Diniz (1279-1325) há documentos com assinaturas neste nome, referentes a João Annes de Villas Boas, senhor da Torre de Airó em Barcelos, Portugal.
No do nobiliário é levantada a possibilidade desse nome ter sido uma corruptela do sobrenome Villabens, na época comum no norte de Portugal.</description></item><item><title>Vintage</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/vintage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/vintage/</guid><description>Wine grapes take an entire season to ripen, and thus, wine is produced just once a year. Hence, the output of a vineyard can be identified by its year. When you see a vintage year listed on the label, that’s the year the grapes were picked and made into wine.</description></item><item><title>Wake Up At The Same Time Every Day</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/wake-up-at-the-same-time-every-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/wake-up-at-the-same-time-every-day/</guid><description>Use the current baseline as starting point. It&amp;rsquo;s more important to be consistent than to be early. The first objective is to get the circadian rhythm in place so it can serve as foundation to a stable routine. To that end, there are two obvious-but-hard-to-execute factors: actually booting up at the planned time and being disciplined with bedtime.
After having the morning routine in place, enter the hard work of building a habit out of it.</description></item><item><title>Wealth Expectation Calculator</title><link>https://victor.villas/independent/wealth-expectation-calculator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/independent/wealth-expectation-calculator/</guid><description>#TODO out of date with latest assumptions in Portifolio Returns
let X = 5000; let R_I = 0.05; let R_F = 0.01; let S = 0.3; var formatter = new Intl.NumberFormat(&amp;#39;en-US&amp;#39;, {style: &amp;#39;currency&amp;#39;,currency: &amp;#39;USD&amp;#39;}); let round = (x) =&amp;gt; (Math.round(100*x)/100).toFixed(2) let wealth = (t) =&amp;gt; ( 6_000_000 * (Math.pow(1.0005, t) - 1) * Math.pow(1.06, Math.floor(t/12)) ); let indexes = [...Array(258).keys()]; dv.table( [&amp;#34;Date&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Wealth&amp;#34;], indexes.map(i =&amp;gt; [ `${2019+Math.floor((5+i)/12)}-${(5+i)%12+1}`, formatter.format(wealth(i+1)), ]) );</description></item><item><title>Web Sign-In</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/web-signin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/web-signin/</guid><description>Web Sign-In is an authentication method where the identity is based on a web address. A client that supports Web Sign-In will then inspect the given address to find an authorization method to use as next step.
One common implementation of Web Sign-In is RelMeAuth, which uses rel=me links to find a service to which authentication can be delegated. Another option is IndieAuth, where the client negotiates with a specified authorization endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Whiskey Lactone</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/whiskey-lactone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/whiskey-lactone/</guid><description>Coconut, bourbon whiskey.
Comes from the barrels.</description></item><item><title>Willpower</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/willpower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/willpower/</guid><description>The hurdles when following the good path Stimulus Rush We are equipped with various legacy rewards mechanisms that companies learned how to manipulate to the point of abuse. Porn, games, drugs, social networks, junk food. Many products maximize the stimuli and overshoot the healthy thresholds of our built-in reward systems, creating vice and hurting our self control. Slippery Slope Very tightly planned routines are also very unstable because they have a greater attack surface for unforeseen circumstances.</description></item><item><title>Wine Blends</title><link>https://victor.villas/sommelier/wine-blends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/sommelier/wine-blends/</guid><description>A wine blend is a wine made with a blend of several Grape Varieties. Blending is a traditional winemaking method, and today there are several famous wine blends produced in classic winemaking regions. Most wine blends are mixed after the fermentation (and aging) is complete. When grapes are blended and fermented together it is called a field blend. A famous example of a field blend is Port Wine.</description></item></channel></rss>