<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>🤝 Socializer on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/</link><description>Recent content in 🤝 Socializer on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/socializer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Combine Comfort With Effort</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/combine-comfort-with-effort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/combine-comfort-with-effort/</guid><description>Because Corresponding Affection Can Be Hard, it&amp;rsquo;s important to guarantee that an attempt will be made. In this case, one way to segue into an affection demonstration with a decreased risk of last-minute second thoughts is to plan ahead an easy start.
For example, for someone that finds hard to initiate with verbal affirmation or physical intimacy, waking up early and making breakfast will get things in motion. The other person will initiate a &amp;ldquo;thank you&amp;rdquo; or a hug that to be corresponded.</description></item><item><title>Corresponding Affection Can Be Hard</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/corresponding-affection-can-be-hard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/corresponding-affection-can-be-hard/</guid><description>Each person might be attuned to demonstrate affection in different ways. For example: verbal affirmation, being present, physical intimacy, gifting, proactive help, respecting space.
Most people will have a few preferred channels to demonstrate affection, which may or may not be their most attuned channel to perceive affection from others. Some people might even be fluent in all of them.
Whatever the case, it can be hard to correspond a demonstration of affection in the same manner if it comes through a channel that is a bit underdeveloped on the receiving side.</description></item><item><title>Listen To The Sound Of Silence</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/listen-to-the-sound-of-silence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/listen-to-the-sound-of-silence/</guid><description>An Aphorism conveying the importance of active listening and achieving empathy.
Interpretation Hold talking, keep listening. Give some time for words to be processed into meaning.
Wait for silence, let it be, &amp;ldquo;listen&amp;rdquo; to it (meaning, evaluate it) as much as you were listening to the spoken words before.
What kind of silence is it? Is it a post-rant silence? A help-seeking silence? A comfort-needing silence? Listen to how that silence sounds.</description></item><item><title>Meetup Tracking</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/meetup-tracking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/meetup-tracking/</guid><description>The contact evaluation metric considers three aspects: availability, friendliness, and initiative. Each aspect is graded in the set {1, 2, 3, 4} according to the following criteria:
Availability Requires week-long planning or more Requires up to a day or two of planning Planning preferred but doable by end of day Could happen almost any time without notice Friendliness Some topics are preferably avoided Conversations are relaxed by default Frequently one loses track of time Tempting to keep going for an all-nighter Initiative Rarely initiates a conversation Sometimes initiates a conversation Frequently hits up for a chat or a meet Invites for all sorts of activities</description></item><item><title>Social Operating System</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/social-operating-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/social-operating-system/</guid><description>The Social Operating System is a set of processes and tools aiming:
To maintain a healthy social circle as a functioning adult; To prevent important relationships from attention starvation; To filter out relationships not worth the maintenance investment. The processes are:
The periodic Meetup Tracking The tools are:
Documentation Instagram WhatsApp</description></item><item><title>TBD Title - Be Serious when Surprised</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/tbd-title--be-serious-when-surprised/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/tbd-title--be-serious-when-surprised/</guid><description>#TODO 😊 Serious when surprised Não rir, levar mais a sério / Risível = ridículo</description></item><item><title>There's A Language Without Question Marks</title><link>https://victor.villas/socializer/theres-a-language-without-question-marks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/socializer/theres-a-language-without-question-marks/</guid><description>An Aphorism conveying the parsimony of questioning as a mean to connect instead of probing to dissect.
Interpretation Hold questioning, keep listening. Give some space for words to be processed into meaning.
Words are ambiguous because reality is ambiguous. Analyzing it can be useful, but being useful is not always the most important goal.
What is the big picture? Is there a way to understand this language without getting lost on the river of symbols?</description></item></channel></rss>