<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>☕️ Barista on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/</link><description>Recent content in ☕️ Barista on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/barista/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bean Blends</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</guid><description>Most of commercially available ground coffees are blends of multiple Coffee Beans, as opposed to Single Origin Beans coffee which includes only coffee beans coming from the same location.
Regular coffee are usually blends because the beans used aren&amp;rsquo;t really high grade and are not thoroughly tracked. Specialty Coffee blends on the other hand are an art form on their own.
A good blend recipe has to combine multiple beans in a complementary way, achieving a flavor combination that no Single Origin Beans coffee could.</description></item><item><title>Brew Strength</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</guid><description>The strength of a coffee brew level is a measure of how noticeable is the flavor in the resulting beverage. Pretty simply, it describes how much of the stuff in the cup is &amp;ldquo;not water&amp;rdquo;.
Strength is directly quantified by the concentration of coffee extract present in the solution. A very diluted coffee is &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; or watery, while a highly concentrated coffee is said to be &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo;. This concentration can be measured with a digital refractometer and is usually defined by the Total Dissolved Solids (TDS) since soluble solids in the Coffee Extract are the main responsible for the flavor.</description></item><item><title>Brewing Control Chart</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</guid><description>The brewing control chart represents brewed coffee flavor profiles as regions on a chart of Brew Strength and Extraction Yield.
The chart is divided into nine regions based on specified lower and upper limits for each variable. The vertical axis corresponds to Brew Strength measured in total dissolved solids (TDS) and Extraction Yield measured in mass concentration of dissolved coffee solids. These two specifications overlap to produce a box in the centre of the chart that indicates the most desirable cup of filter coffee.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</guid><description>Coffee Beans come from cherries which grow on the coffee plant.
There are two main plant species of coffee used for consumption: Arabica (Coffea arabica) and Canephora (Coffea canephora). The Canephora species has a most famous variety named Robusta, commonly used as metonym for the species. Robusta is also known as Conilon in Brazil.
The Canephora species is considered to be an ancestor to the Arabica species, but there&amp;rsquo;s also evidence that the better flavor from Arabica was inherited from the Eugenioides species (Coffea eugenioides).</description></item><item><title>Coffee Extract</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</guid><description>Roasted coffee is made up of some soluble solids and mostly insoluble solids (mainly cellulose) as well as volatiles that are liberated as gases. The composition depends on the species and variety of the Coffee Beans, the Coffee Fruit Processing, the Roasting and Extraction Methods used.
The soluble solids that are dissolved contribute the most to the brew taste and strength. The volatile soluble compounds contribute to its aroma. Caffeine in particular is among the most soluble components of ground coffee and is extracted early in the process.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Fruit Processing</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</guid><description>The coffee fruit/cherry can be subdivided in:
The seed Bean (endosperm) Silver Skin (spermoderm) Parchment (endocarp) Pulp (mesocarp) Skin (exocarp) The term processing in specialty coffee refers to the methods and preparation used to turn fresh ripe coffee cherries into green beans (which will go through Roasting next). This includes removing the bean from the fruit/cherry (depulping), fermenting and drying the beans. This can be done in several different styles, the 3 most basic methods being Natural, Washing and Honey processing and they have a big impact on the final flavor of the coffee.</description></item><item><title>Cupping</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</guid><description>Coffee Cupping or Coffee Tasting is the practice of observing the taste and aromatics of a Coffee Extract to evaluate its flavor.
It&amp;rsquo;s an industry practice that can be done informally by anyone or with strict protocols and guidelines by professionals. It involves evaluating the coffee after roasting by grinding the beans and steeping it with hot water in cupping bowls for a set amount of time (a very simple and easy to reproduce Immersion Brewing technique).</description></item><item><title>Espresso</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</guid><description>Bean Preparation RDT: Spray or Drop or the Spoon Method Not every grinder has low retention, it&amp;rsquo;s important to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re getting out what you put in.
Puck Preparation Make sure the puck is absolutely dry. Dosing funnel helps with distribution as well.
Distribution. The objective is to have an homogeneous and even bed of coffee to avoid uneven flow. To remove the clumps, use a needled tool to stir and move around the coffee inside.</description></item><item><title>Extraction Methods</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1</description></item><item><title>Extraction Yield</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</guid><description>The Extraction Yield, plotted on the horizontal axis, is considered the key measure of coffee flavor.
It is the percentage of the dry coffee bed mass extracted into the beverage.
$$ \frac{\mbox{Yield} \times \mbox{TDS}}{\mbox{Dose}} = \mbox{Extraction Yield} $$ Where the $\mbox{Dose}$ means the weight of coffee used in the recipe, $\mbox{Yield}$ is the total weight of the coffee produced and $\mbox{TDS}$ is the concentration of dissolved solids.
#TODO expand</description></item><item><title>Fines Migration</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</guid><description>Using filter paper
https://www.baristahustle.com/blog/fines-migration/
#TODO cite M Petracco, 2005. Percolation. In: A Illy and R Viana (Eds), Espresso Coffee: The Science of Quality, second edition (pp 259-287)</description></item><item><title>Grinding</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</guid><description>In the grinding of coffee, the particle size distribution is the main concern. Finer particles will be more subject to extraction than bigger particles because they have more surface area per volume. Generally speaking, a good grind is a highly concentrated distribution of particle sizes, meaning uniformity of sizes. Total uniformity is not an absolute goal, however, because some diversity of sizes can be useful: having a bit of fines (a nickname for particles much smaller than the bulk of the distribution, usually smaller than $100 \mu m$ and consisting of mostly of bean skin, i.</description></item><item><title>Moka</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</guid><description>#TODO translate
Cafeteira Italiana (Moka) A cafeteira italiana é um dos métodos mais tradicionais e democráticos de se fazer café. Uma vez descoberta a &amp;ldquo;receita&amp;rdquo; ideal para sua cafeteira e café escolhidos, ela é fácil e consistente. Com ela, é possível trazer um café muito semelhante a um espresso para dentro de casa.
Procedimento No entanto, para quem ainda não encontrou a receita ideal ela pode ser um pouco difícil de domar.</description></item><item><title>No-Bypass Filter Brew</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a concept around pour-over coffee.
Some of the water goes side-ways in the filter and around the coffee. That water is called bypass water.
The more water goes through coffee, the more solubles down the cup. Less bypass means more effective and efficient extraction. A stronger extraction.
Aeropress is zero-bypass, espresso as well. But water doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through coffee, it takes pressure.
Models: Tricolate Next Level</description></item><item><title>Pour Over</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</guid><description>Bypass with frilled filters/drippers.
Recipes 15g / 255g (1:17) 45g bloom (2 minutes) All the way (2 minutes) Swirling</description></item><item><title>Roasting</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</guid><description>Coffee Beans will naturally have their levels of acidity and sweetness. The toasty, nutty or roasted flavors only develop from roasting where sugars from coffee are caramelized;
#TODO https://associatedcoffee.com/blog/how-coffee-changes-during-the-roasting-process/ #TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
However, the darker the roast doesn’t mean the better the brew as this is a common misconception. The beans should be roasted to a point where the preferred flavor profiles are highlighted and this generally happens between in a light to medium roast.</description></item><item><title>Single Origin Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
As opposed to Bean Blends. Common in Specialty Coffee.</description></item><item><title>Specialty Coffee</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1</description></item><item><title>Sweetness</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</guid><description>Coffee is often compared in terms of sweetness and is common to see tasters describe a brew as &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; during Cupping, but coffee has no sugars and it&amp;rsquo;s not fully understood what exactly we are describing as sweet.
Coffee beans do contain sucrose, but the roasting process degrades about 97% of it. The amount of sucrose that ends up in the brew is so low that it&amp;rsquo;s below the sensory threshold concentration, meaning it is impossible for us to perceive it.</description></item></channel></rss>