<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>☕️ Barista on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/</link><description>Recent content in ☕️ Barista on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/barista/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bach's Coffee Cantata</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/bachs-coffee-cantata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/bachs-coffee-cantata/</guid><description>Schweigt stille, plaudert nicht (Be still, stop chattering), also known as the Coffee Cantata, is a secular cantata by Johann Sebastian Bach, composed probably between 1732 and 1735. Although classified as a cantata, it is essentially a miniature comic opera. In a satirical commentary, the cantata amusingly tells of a woman&amp;rsquo;s dependence on coffee.
BWV 211-212 in Apple Music (lyrics)
The work lampoons both the wild popularity of coffee in 18th century Leipzig, as well as the mildly sanctimonious belief held by some of Leipzig society at the time that coffee drinking was a bad habit that needed to be broken.</description></item><item><title>Bean Blends</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/bean-blends/</guid><description>Most of commercially available ground coffees are blends of multiple Coffee Beans, as opposed to Single Origin Beans coffee which includes only coffee beans coming from the same location.
Regular coffee are usually blends because the beans used aren&amp;rsquo;t really high grade and are not thoroughly tracked. Specialty Coffee blends on the other hand are an art form on their own.
A good blend recipe has to combine multiple beans in a complementary way, achieving a flavor combination that no Single Origin Beans coffee could.</description></item><item><title>Brew Strength</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brew-strength/</guid><description>The strength of a coffee brew level is a measure of how noticeable is the flavor in the resulting beverage. Pretty simply, it describes how much of the stuff in the cup is not water. This is why strength is a property of a brew, not a quality determined by the beans.
Strength is directly quantified by the concentration of coffee extract present in the solution. A very diluted coffee is &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; or watery, while a highly concentrated coffee is said to be &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Brewing Control Chart</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/brewing-control-chart/</guid><description>The brewing control chart represents brewed coffee flavor profiles as regions on a chart of Brew Strength and Extraction Yield. The chart is divided into nine regions based on specified lower and upper limits for each variable. The vertical axis corresponds to Brew Strength measured in total dissolved solids (TDS) and Extraction Yield measured in mass concentration of dissolved coffee solids. These two specifications overlap to produce a box in the centre of the chart that indicates the most desirable cup of filter coffee.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-beans/</guid><description>Coffee Beans come from cherries which grow on the coffee plant.
There are two main plant species of coffee used for consumption: Arabica (Coffea arabica) and Canephora (Coffea canephora). The Canephora species has a most famous variety named Robusta, commonly used as metonym for the species. Robusta is also known as Conilon in Brazil.
The Canephora species is considered to be an ancestor to the Arabica species, but there&amp;rsquo;s also evidence that the better flavor from Arabica was inherited from the Eugenioides species (Coffea eugenioides).</description></item><item><title>Coffee Culture</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-culture/</guid><description>Coffee In the Arts
Bach&amp;rsquo;s Coffee Cantata London&amp;rsquo;s 1674 Petition Against Coffee Sources Eighteenth-Century Coffee-House Culture Edited by Markman Ellis, this four-volume set reprints facsimile satires, plays and histories of the period: Restoration Satire, The Eighteenth-Century Satire, Drama, Science and History Writings. A great resource for archivists and researchers.
The Coffee House: A Cultural History Another book by Markman Ellis, more friendly to coffee lovers and the general public but still well researched and scholarly enough to be a good read for historians - still focused on 18th century England.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Extract</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-extract/</guid><description>Roasted coffee is made up of some soluble solids and mostly insoluble solids (mainly cellulose) as well as volatiles that are liberated as gases. The composition depends on the species and variety of the Coffee Beans, the Coffee Fruit Processing, the Roasting and Extraction Methods used.
The soluble solids that are dissolved contribute the most to the brew taste and strength. The volatile soluble compounds contribute to its aroma. Caffeine in particular is among the most soluble components of ground coffee and is extracted early in the process.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Fruit Processing</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-fruit-processing/</guid><description>The coffee fruit/cherry can be subdivided in:
The seed Bean (endosperm) Silver Skin (spermoderm) Parchment (endocarp) Pulp (mesocarp) Skin (exocarp) The term processing in specialty coffee refers to the methods and preparation used to turn fresh ripe coffee cherries into green beans (which will go through Roasting next). This includes removing the bean from the fruit/cherry (depulping), fermenting and drying the beans. This can be done in several different styles, the 3 most common methods being Natural, Washing and Honey processing and they have a big impact on the final flavor of the coffee.</description></item><item><title>Coffee Grading</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-grading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/coffee-grading/</guid><description>Roasted Bean Grading ABIC&amp;rsquo;s PQC Categories #TODO
Tradicional: At least 70% arabica, no more than 20% PVA defects. Superior: At least 85% arabica, no more than 10% PVA defects. Gourmet/Premium: 100% arabica, 0% of PVA defects.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a sustainability certification add-on, requiring at least 60% must be sourced from certified sustainable sources.
BSCA Certification #TODO
Green Bean Grading When buying green beans to be roasted, #TODO
SCA&amp;rsquo;s Green Coffee Grading Protocol The SCA defines a Green Arabica Coffee Classification System (GACCS) based on counting defects on a 350 g sample of beans.</description></item><item><title>Cupping</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/cupping/</guid><description>Coffee Cupping or Coffee Tasting is the practice of observing the taste and aromatics of a Coffee Extract to evaluate its flavor.
It&amp;rsquo;s an industry practice that can be done informally by anyone or with strict protocols and guidelines by professionals. It involves evaluating the coffee after roasting by grinding the beans and steeping it with hot water in cupping bowls for a set amount of time (a very simple and easy to reproduce Immersion Brewing technique).</description></item><item><title>Degassing</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/degassing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/degassing/</guid><description>#TODO https://pubs.acs.org/doi/full/10.1021/acs.jafc.7b03310 #TODO https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2214289422000850 #TODO https://digitalcollection.zhaw.ch/handle/11475/13126</description></item><item><title>Dialing Espresso</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/dialing-espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/dialing-espresso/</guid><description>Grind size: Finer grinds opens more surface area thus more extraction. Ratio/Extraction Yield: how much espresso you&amp;rsquo;re pulling out of the original dose. Temperature: higher temperature means higher extraction. 90~96 C Pressure/Flow Rate: higher pressure increases extraction.
How to get a head start just from the coffee description?
Variety: Catura, Catuaí, Gueisha, Maragogipe etc. Processing: Natural, Washed, Honey etc. Roast Level: Light, Medium, Dark.
Airloom is dense, hence difficult to extract, hence we need more extraction.</description></item><item><title>Dosing Ratios</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/dosing-ratios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/dosing-ratios/</guid><description>Ratios are usually noted as (grams of coffee) to (grams of water), for example 1:16. That&amp;rsquo;s fine if one is usually brewing the mostly the same amount of coffee on every recipe, but a bit backwards if it comes to the situation of figuring out how much coffee to grind to serve some guests. In that case, measuring ratios as (grams of coffee) per (liters of water) is more intuitive and usually results in simpler math.</description></item><item><title>Espresso</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/espresso/</guid><description>Bean Preparation RDT: Spray or Drop or the Spoon Method Not every grinder has low retention, it&amp;rsquo;s important to make sure you&amp;rsquo;re getting out what you put in.
Puck Preparation Make sure the puck is absolutely dry. Dosing funnel helps with distribution as well.
Distribution. The objective is to have an homogeneous and even bed of coffee to avoid uneven flow. To remove the clumps, use a needled tool to stir and move around the coffee inside.</description></item><item><title>Extraction Methods</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-methods/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1</description></item><item><title>Extraction Yield</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/extraction-yield/</guid><description>The Extraction Yield, plotted on the horizontal axis, is considered the key measure of coffee flavor.
It is the percentage of the dry coffee bed mass extracted into the beverage.
$$ \frac{\mbox{Yield} \times \mbox{TDS}}{\mbox{Dose}} = \mbox{Extraction Yield} $$ Where the $\mbox{Dose}$ means the weight of coffee used in the recipe, $\mbox{Yield}$ is the total weight of the coffee produced and $\mbox{TDS}$ is the concentration of dissolved solids.
#TODO expand #TODO https://awasteof.</description></item><item><title>Fines Migration</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/fines-migration/</guid><description>Using filter paper
https://www.baristahustle.com/blog/fines-migration/
#TODO cite M Petracco, 2005. Percolation. In: A Illy and R Viana (Eds), Espresso Coffee: The Science of Quality, second edition (pp 259-287)</description></item><item><title>Grinding</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/grinding/</guid><description>In the grinding of coffee, the particle size distribution is the main concern. Finer particles will be more subject to extraction than bigger particles because they have more surface area per volume. Generally speaking, a good grind is a highly concentrated distribution of particle sizes, meaning uniformity of sizes. Total uniformity is not an absolute goal, however, because some diversity of sizes can be useful: having a bit of fines (a nickname for particles much smaller than the bulk of the distribution, usually smaller than $100 \mu m$ and consisting of mostly of bean skin, i.</description></item><item><title>Latte Art</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/latte-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/latte-art/</guid><description>Spout Proximity The further up you are, the more swaying and swirling happens, blurring the design.
Starting Point Don&amp;rsquo;t start in the center, start higher. The more drops necessary, the deeper the start can be because the ripples will move around.
Pushing Forward Move backward as little as possible, only necessary if the design requires it.</description></item><item><title>Lever Espresso Maker</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/lever-espresso-maker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/lever-espresso-maker/</guid><description>Flair 58 https://flairespresso.com/product/flair-58/
Accessories https://www.naked-portafilter.com/smart-espresso-profiler/</description></item><item><title>London's 1674 Petition Against Coffee</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/londons-1674-petition-against-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/londons-1674-petition-against-coffee/</guid><description>The Women&amp;rsquo;s Petition Against Coffee, Representing to Public Consideration the Grand INCONVENIENCES accruing to their SEX from the Excessive Use of that Drying, Enfeebling LIQUOR, Presented to the Right Honorable the Keepers of the Liberty of VENUS, by a Well-willer. London, Printed 1674.
The petition protested against the consumption of coffee arguing that it made men sterile and impotent and stated that it contributed to the nation&amp;rsquo;s failing birth rate. According to the petition, coffee made men &amp;ldquo;as unfruitful as the sandy deserts, from where that unhappy berry is said to be brought.</description></item><item><title>Moka</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/moka/</guid><description>#TODO translate
Cafeteira Italiana (Moka) A cafeteira italiana é um dos métodos mais tradicionais e democráticos de se fazer café. Uma vez descoberta a &amp;ldquo;receita&amp;rdquo; ideal para sua cafeteira e café escolhidos, ela é fácil e consistente. Com ela, é possível trazer um café muito semelhante a um espresso para dentro de casa.
Procedimento No entanto, para quem ainda não encontrou a receita ideal ela pode ser um pouco difícil de domar.</description></item><item><title>No-Bypass Filter Brew</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/nobypass-filter-brew/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a concept around pour-over coffee.
Some of the water goes side-ways in the filter and around the coffee. That water is called bypass water.
The more water goes through coffee, the more solubles down the cup. Less bypass means more effective and efficient extraction. A stronger extraction.
Aeropress is zero-bypass, espresso as well. But water doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to go through coffee, it takes pressure.
Models: Tricolate Next Level</description></item><item><title>Pour Over</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/pour-over/</guid><description>Bypass with frilled filters/drippers.
Rinse out the paper + filter. It will remove paper taste and pre-heat the filter. Add the grounds and create a little well in the middle of the grounds.
See also No-Bypass Filter Brew.
Recipes Hoffman&amp;rsquo;s Ultimate V60 Bloom with 2-3 x dose (30 to 45 seconds rest) Swirl during bloom as well Pour 60% of total target in 30 seconds. That&amp;rsquo;s enough to give it a good agitation but not too much.</description></item><item><title>Roasting</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/roasting/</guid><description>Roasting is the final processing step before the Coffee Beans can be finally consumed, after Coffee Fruit Processing. It plays a major role on the final flavor profile of the Coffee Extract, as though beans will naturally have their different characteristics, their chemical composition is dramatically affected by the roasting process (pyrolysis).
For example, roasting affects the solubility of carbohydrates. Increased degrees of roasting increase the solubility of galactomannans, but too much roasting leads to degradation of arabinogalactans.</description></item><item><title>Single Origin Beans</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/single-origin-beans/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
As opposed to Bean Blends. Common in Specialty Coffee.</description></item><item><title>Specialty Coffee</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/specialty-coffee/</guid><description>#TODO https://codeblackcoffee.com.au/blogs/coffee-notes/coffee-module-1
For coffee to be labelled as specialty it needs to reach a score of over 80/100 when coffee gets cupped by industry professionals (usually certified graders).
The Brazilian Association of the Coffee Industry (ABIC) introduced a quality rating system based on bean defects:
Tradicional: between 4,5 and 6,0 Superior: between 6 and 7,2 Gourmet: between 7,3 and 10 But it also uses the Especial denomination for Specialty Coffee as defined by the SCA, adopted by the Brazilian Specialty Coffee Association (BSCA).</description></item><item><title>Sustainability</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/sustainability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/sustainability/</guid><description>#TODO Rainforest Alliance / Utz Certified Cafés Sustentáveis do Brasil (Abic)</description></item><item><title>Sweetness</title><link>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/barista/sweetness/</guid><description>Sugar and Sweetness Sweetness is a basic taste most commonly perceived when eating foods rich in certain substances (usually carbohydrates) called sugars. Simple sugars (monosaccharides) include glucose, fructose, and galactose. Compound sugars (disaccharides) are molecules made of two bonded monosaccharides; common examples are sucrose (glucose + fructose), lactose (glucose + galactose), and maltose (two molecules of glucose). Chains of monosaccharides longer than two are not regarded as sugars and are called oligosaccharides or polysaccharides.</description></item></channel></rss>