<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>📟 Technophile on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/</link><description>Recent content in 📟 Technophile on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/technophile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Activate Lost Mode</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/activate-lost-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/activate-lost-mode/</guid><description>Se você for assaltado e forçado a entregar o PIN que desbloqueia o seu iPhone, você deve:
Bloquear o seu iPhone pelo iCloud Entrar no icloud.com; entrar na sessão &amp;ldquo;Find iPhone&amp;rdquo;'; selecionar o seu dispositivo roubado colocar no modo &amp;ldquo;Lost Mode&amp;rdquo; Bloquear o seu cartão SIM pela operadora Ligar para sua operadora (ou entrar na área de cliente do site); pedir bloqueio do chip (pelo IMEI) ou da linha (pelo número) Esses dois passos devem ser feitos o mais rápido possível pois com seu celular desbloqueado, o ladrão terá acesso ao seus e-mails, SMS e WhatsApp.</description></item><item><title>Bellroy Tech Kit</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/bellroy-tech-kit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/bellroy-tech-kit/</guid><description>https://bellroy.com/products/tech-kit/looma_viroblock_standard/basalt#slide-0
https://bellroy.com/promotions/2021/youtube?promotional-campaign=daniel-titchener-hjsdb-sdhje</description></item><item><title>Hide Notification Previews</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/hide-notification-previews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/hide-notification-previews/</guid><description>This will protect your privacy by not allowing whoever possesses your smartphone to read any messages you receive, transactions, e-mails and so on.</description></item><item><title>Matching Iphone wallpapers to modular watch face color gradients</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/matching-iphone-wallpapers-to-modular-watch-face-color-gradients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/matching-iphone-wallpapers-to-modular-watch-face-color-gradients/</guid><description>This is surprisingly hard. It&amp;rsquo;s already hard to get an accurate capture of the watch face colors. For some reason if you take a screen capture on your watch the colors will not perfectly match what your eyes are seeing on the device display - perhaps color calibration or brightness effects?
If you have any knowledge on this or would like to suggest a correction, please reach out. The only way I found to go through this is by using the color picker on watch face previews and then eye-balling a correction to brightness and tones so it will look as I wanted.</description></item><item><title>MINIX 3-Port Wall Charger</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/minix-3port-wall-charger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/minix-3port-wall-charger/</guid><description>https://www.amazon.co.uk/MINIX-Charger-Charging-Adapter-Compatible/dp/B08M3L8BFT/ref=sr_1_5?crid=2YXG0UUEZ9JU9&amp;keywords=minix+charger&amp;qid=1645982352&amp;sprefix=minix+charger%2Caps%2C85&amp;sr=8-5</description></item><item><title>Require Unlock for Control Center</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/require-unlock-for-control-center/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/require-unlock-for-control-center/</guid><description>Um celular roubado imediatamente colocado em modo avião não vai mais transmitir sua posição ou se comunicar com a Internet, o que impede sua localização e o funcionamento da funcionalidade de &amp;ldquo;Marcar como Perdido&amp;rdquo; ou &amp;ldquo;Apagar Dispositivo&amp;rdquo;. Enquanto isso o assaltante pode usar as funcionalidades offline como ver seus contatos, suas fotos e arquivos locais, seus e-mails baixados anteriormente etc.
Para mitigar esse risco, você pode configurar o seu iPhone para exigir</description></item><item><title>Smartphone Hardening</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/smartphone-hardening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/smartphone-hardening/</guid><description>Threat Level: stolen while locked Use a Passphrase as Lock Screen passcode to reduce the odds of it being guessed and remembered by others Hide Notification Previews in the Lock Screen to prevent others from seeing private content without unlocking Use a SIM card PIN to lock your SIM if transferred to a different device or if the phone is turned off and on again Require Unlock for Control Center to prevent others from turning off GPS or mobile data without turning off the phone Threat Level: stolen while unlocked Trusted Phone Number de outra pessoa iOS Content Restrictions (Screen Time) Use um app de E-mail com senha própria Threat Level: stolen with passcode #TODO time restriction iCloud with password Countermeasures:</description></item><item><title>Use a Passphrase</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-passphrase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-passphrase/</guid><description>Instead of simple numeric passcodes or complex random strings mixed with special characters, use a passphrase as your &amp;ldquo;Custom Alphanumeric&amp;rdquo; passcode.
https://www.useapassphrase.com/
You will have to type this password once in a while and this can be a bit annoying, but 99% of the time you&amp;rsquo;ll get by with biometrics so it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it seems.
This is an important passcode and it should be stored in your Password Manager.</description></item><item><title>Use a Password Manager</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-password-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-password-manager/</guid><description>Sharing password between different services is bad information security hygiene. You would need to keep track of all the data breaches going on around the world - and when one does inevitably happen, begins the nightmare of updating said password everywhere you&amp;rsquo;ve been using it.
Using variations of a main password doesn&amp;rsquo;t work either. If your variation technique is simple enough to be easy to remember, it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough for a computer to guess.</description></item><item><title>Use a SIM card PIN</title><link>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-sim-card-pin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/technophile/use-a-sim-card-pin/</guid><description>Mesmo que o seu celular seja roubado sem o passcode, é possível pegar o SIM e colocar em outro celular para receber SMS e receber ligações (enquanto você não fizer o bloqueio do chip).
Assim como você pode ter um PIN para o iPhone, é possível escolher um outro PIN específico para o seu cartão SIM. Esse PIN é exigido sempre que o celular tenta estabelecer conectividade com a sua operadora.</description></item></channel></rss>