<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>📷 Photographer on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/</link><description>Recent content in 📷 Photographer on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/photographer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aperture</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/aperture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/aperture/</guid><description>The aperture is the opening that allows light into the camera. A wider or narrower opening changes the amount (and direction diversity) of light that comes through during the time the shutter is open.
Apertures are usually described by an f-number: the ratio of the system&amp;rsquo;s Focal Length to the diameter of the aperture. This means that a f/4 aperture is bigger than a f/8 aperture, in fact twice as big in diameter.</description></item><item><title>Camera App Configurations For Photography</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-app-configurations-for-photography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-app-configurations-for-photography/</guid><description>These settings are based on the Halide app, but most apps have similar options available.
Let the Grid ON by default to help you with the Rule of Thirds and leveling Let the Exposure Histogram ON by default to help preventing a skewed exposure Let Auto Focus ON in the Focus Ring because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Set Raw+ as the capture mode to save Raw for editing and HEIC for quick sharing Let Coverage OFF to speed up capture as default HEIC is usually good enough Let Auto White Balance ON because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Let Auto Exposure ON by default because it&amp;rsquo;s easier and often enough Let Zebras ON to help detect color Clipping due to skewed exposure</description></item><item><title>Camera ISO</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-iso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/camera-iso/</guid><description>ISO controls the sensitivity of the camera. This means that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t control the amount of light entering the camera, but how the camera should interpret the light coming in.
A higher ISO means higher sensitivity, therefore a brighter image for the same amount of light captured. It&amp;rsquo;s useful to raise the ISO when there&amp;rsquo;s no other way to increase brightness (e.g. a slower shutter would add blur and wider aperture would decrease depth of field).</description></item><item><title>Depth of Field</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/depth-of-field/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/depth-of-field/</guid><description>The depth of field is the range of the scene that appears sharp, commonly said to be &amp;ldquo;in Focus&amp;rdquo;. It is determined by the Focal Length and the Aperture diameter.
For landscape photos, the depth of field has to be huge (kilometers). For portrait photos, the depth of field might be just a few centimeters. The ideal depth of field depends on what the subject of the photo is and where/if it&amp;rsquo;s desirable to isolate the rest of the image.</description></item><item><title>Editing on Adobe Lightroom</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/editing-on-adobe-lightroom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/editing-on-adobe-lightroom/</guid><description>Adobe Lightroom is a popular photo editing application, available on smartphones, tablets and desktop.
Light Adjustments The most common task is correcting for white balance.
#TODO What is the tone curve?
Burning and Dodging: make bright brighter and dark darker
Brightness controls the overall look from bright to dark
Contrast (the ratio between highlights and shadows)
Highlights controls the brightness/contrast of the brightest parts of the image
Shadows controls the brightness/contrast of the darkest parts of the image #TODO histogram analysis of highlights vs whites, shadows vs blacks</description></item><item><title>Exposure</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/exposure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/exposure/</guid><description>Camera exposure controls the amount of light (per unit area) received by the camera, affecting the image brightness.
The luminous exposure is controlled by two settings: Shutter Speed and Aperture. Changing the Camera ISO also affects the brightness of photos and some apps might tinker with it when adjusting exposure, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t technically change the amount of light that enters the camera - just the sensitivity of the sensors inside the camera.</description></item><item><title>F-number Equivalence</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/fnumber-equivalence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/fnumber-equivalence/</guid><description>Given a lens described by an f-number, its effect on Exposure is the same no matter the sensor size of the camera. That&amp;rsquo;s why f-number is useful in the first place: to reduce the Focal Length and Aperture diameter combination into a single variable that completely describes the lens influence on Exposure.
However, different sensor sizes will play a role on the Depth of Field. After adjusting for Focal Length Equivalence (choosing a focal length that yields equivalent framing and perspective), the depth of field is then determined by the Aperture diameter.</description></item><item><title>Focal Length</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length/</guid><description>In technical terms, the focal point is the geometric place where parallel light rays converge after passing through a lens. In photography, the focal point stays at a small distance from the camera sensors called focal length.
A longer focal length means that light rays coming from objects far away will converge way before reaching the sensors, so they will disperse and the object will appear more blurry. Conversely, light rays coming from objects very near the camera will tend to converge further behind the sensors and will appear more blurry as well.</description></item><item><title>Focal Length Equivalence</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length-equivalence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focal-length-equivalence/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Focus</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/focus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/focus/</guid><description>An object is said to be focused when its image appears &amp;ldquo;sharp&amp;rdquo;, meaning its edges are clearly defined.
To adjust an image focus is to determine the placement of objects in relation to the Depth of Field. Objects inside this region will appear sharp because the light rays reflected by these objects will converge to a point close to the camera sensors.</description></item><item><title>Halide</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/halide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/halide/</guid><description>Auto Focus Mode In automatic Focus mode, it&amp;rsquo;s still possible to tweak the focus by tapping on the viewfinder. Halide will focus on the objects at that region of the image.
Manual Focus Mode Lower numbers focus on closer objects, higher numbers focus on far away objects.
Use the Focus Loupe as a visual aide to the sharpness of an object in the center of the image. If focusing on multiple objects or an entire section of the scene, the Focus Peaking works as a visual indicator of sharp edges on the image.</description></item><item><title>Have Two Camera Apps On Your Phone</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/have-two-camera-apps-on-your-phone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/have-two-camera-apps-on-your-phone/</guid><description>This is a tip for those who want to take serious photography but not really always. There are several situational configurations on camera apps that stay in place after your last use and it can be a hassle to undo them when you just want to snap a quick photo.
Choose a good alternative camera app (e.g. Halide) to be the one for &amp;ldquo;serious photography&amp;rdquo; and set the usual Camera App Configurations For Photography.</description></item><item><title>iPhone Specific Considerations</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/iphone-specific-considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/iphone-specific-considerations/</guid><description>iPhone cameras lenses do not have movable iris so the Aperture isn&amp;rsquo;t adjustable. Instead, Apple provides different lenses with combinations of Aperture and Focal Length. For example, the iPhone 13 Pro has:
Ultra wide Lens -&amp;gt; 13 mm focal length, f/1.8 aperture Wide Lens -&amp;gt; 26 mm focal length, f/1.5 aperture Telephoto Lens -&amp;gt; 77 mm focal length, f/2.8 aperture #TODO https://www.dpreview.com/articles/6780391159/all-apple-iphone-13-and-13-pro-camera-upgrades-explained #TODO https://www.dpreview.com/articles/2666934640/what-is-equivalence-and-why-should-i-care
Portrait Mode works better with the 2x lens and it allows the adjustment of f-stop.</description></item><item><title>Lighting</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/lighting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/lighting/</guid><description>There are 3 main aspects to consider in a light source: the color, the strength, and the direction.
The color of the light source refers to the specific color spectrum. Natural sunlight has a very different spectrum than fluorescent white lamps. Natural light tends to produce great photos for many reasons, one of them is that it&amp;rsquo;s a spectrum of light that we are used to appreciate; it feels natural. Of course, this varies with Sun&amp;rsquo;s position and local weather: the mid-day sun is &amp;ldquo;cooler&amp;rdquo; (more blue), specially when it&amp;rsquo;s cloudy, but sunrise and sunset are very &amp;ldquo;warm&amp;rdquo; (more red).</description></item><item><title>Portrait Editing Technique</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/portrait-editing-technique/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/portrait-editing-technique/</guid><description>Portraits are good opportunities to use a shallow Depth of Field, having the focus solely on the main subject. If the photo wasn&amp;rsquo;t taken in such way, a good place to start is to mask the background and add a bit of blur. #TODO how?
Starting with lighting. Portraits usually start with a bright subject, so the idea is to further contrast it with the surroundings. This can be done with a small bump up in Contrast and Highlights plus a notch down on Shadows.</description></item><item><title>Shot Composition</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/shot-composition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/shot-composition/</guid><description>Composition is the art of arranging the objects in the shot with purpose. The subject of the photo should be perceived intuitively, with a guided navigation for the viewers eyes through the important details.
Perspective low angle high angle lateral movement first person POV Vantage Point: points of focus created by leading lines, starting outside the frame and converging inward to a single area of focus Geometric found in objects Organic lines found in nature Rule of Thirds: separate your frame in 9 parts.</description></item><item><title>Shutter Speed</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/shutter-speed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/shutter-speed/</guid><description>Shutter speed controls the amount of time the camera spends taking a picture, that is, absorbing light. This can be a 1/10000 of a second, or an entire hour depending on the camera capabilities. Long times will capture lots of light; short times will capture a little bit of light.
Shutter speed also affects Motion Blur. A moving object will reflect light at multiple locations during the capture interval, reducing image sharpness.</description></item><item><title>Titicaca Lake</title><link>https://victor.villas/photographer/photos/titicaca-lake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/photographer/photos/titicaca-lake/</guid><description>Final Halfway Raw</description></item></channel></rss>