<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>🍲 Culinarian on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/</link><description>Recent content in 🍲 Culinarian on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/culinarian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>_Roadmap</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/_roadmap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/_roadmap/</guid><description>The Tools Pans &amp;amp; Pots Cast-Iron Maintenance Carbon Steel Maintenance Cutting Tools</description></item><item><title>Bacteria vs Heat</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/bacteria-vs-heat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/bacteria-vs-heat/</guid><description>Most bacteria begin to die at 52°C, though it can take upward of 2 hours to safely sterilize food at this temperature.
After about 3 minutes at 64°C, bacteria experience a 7 log reduction - which means that only 1 bacteria will remain for every $10^7$ (million) that were initially there.
At 80°C bacteria experience a 7 log reduction within 1 second.</description></item><item><title>Blade Grip &amp; Claw</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/blade-grip--claw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/blade-grip--claw/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>Carbon Steel Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/carbon-steel-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/carbon-steel-maintenance/</guid><description>#TODO
“Just like a good cast-iron pan, a carbon steel wok’s performance will improve the more you use it. Most come with a protective film of oil to prevent them from rusting or tarnishing in the store. It’s important to remove this layer before using it the first time. Scrub the wok out with hot soapy water, dry it carefully, and place it over a burner at the highest heat possible until it starts to smoke.</description></item><item><title>Cast-Iron Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/castiron-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/castiron-maintenance/</guid><description>#TODO
“When you first get a cast-iron pan, it will have either a bullet-gray dull finish (if it’s an unseasoned pan) or a slick-looking black surface (a preseasoned pan). Unless you bought a seventy-five-year-old pan at a garage sale, it will also have a pebbly-looking surface, like this:Modern cast iron is bumpy like that because it is not polished the way old cast iron was and retains some texture from the mold.</description></item><item><title>Cutting Tools</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/cutting-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/cutting-tools/</guid><description>Materials Ceramic blades are generally a poor choice. They can be ground to a razor-sharp edge and that that edge doesn’t dull even with prolonged use, but their major drawback is that they chip easily and are unrepairable.
Carbon steel is easy to sharpen and it can be ground down into an extraordinarily sharp edge. Its disadvantages are that it dulls relatively quickly, requiring you to resharpen it every few weeks or so to maintain a good cutting edge; it can rust if not cared for properly; and it will discolor if it comes into prolonged contact with acidic fruits or vegetables.</description></item><item><title>Maillard Reaction</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/maillard-reaction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/maillard-reaction/</guid><description>#TODO Maillard browning reactions</description></item><item><title>Pans &amp; Pots</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/pans--pots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/pans--pots/</guid><description>Materials Stainless steel is durable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require too much maintenance, but it also is an extremely poor heat conductor. What this means is that heat will not travel rapidly through it. Stainless steel pans tend to develop distinct hot and cold spots that match the heat pattern of your burners. This can lead to uneven cooking, resulting in, for example, an omelet that’s burned in some spots and still raw in others.</description></item><item><title>Searing Does NOT Seal In its Juices</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/searing-does-not-seal-in-its-juices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/searing-does-not-seal-in-its-juices/</guid><description>The myth that searing the meat &amp;ldquo;seal in&amp;rdquo; its juices comes from a book by Justus von Liebig in 1847. The idea was that the crust would create a barrier that traps the meat juices inside.
Multiple experiments have shown that this is not the case. Harold McGee said on his 1984 book titled On Food and Cooking: “The crust that forms around the surface of the meat is not waterproof, as any cook has experienced: the continuing sizzle of meat in the pan or oven or on the grill is the sound of moisture continually escaping and vaporizing.</description></item><item><title>Sharpening</title><link>https://victor.villas/culinarian/sharpening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/culinarian/sharpening/</guid><description>Most home cooks should sharpen their knives at least twice a year, much more frequently if they use their knives every day.
Use a Sharpening Stone. The best method by far. Not only will it give you the best edge, but it will also remove the least amount of material.
When buying a water stone, look for a large one, at least 2½ inches wide and 8 inches long and an inch thick.</description></item></channel></rss>