<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>⚙️ Systematist on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/</link><description>Recent content in ⚙️ Systematist on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/systematist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aphorism</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/aphorism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/aphorism/</guid><description>An aphorism is a concise, terse, laconic, or memorable expression of a general truth or principle. It&amp;rsquo;s a useful tool for meditation and serves as easy reminders for important lessons or aspirations that could use a bit more attention.
Examples:
Listen To The Sound Of Silence There&amp;rsquo;s A Language Without Question Marks TBD Title - Be Serious when Surprised TBD Title - Assume Nothing</description></item><item><title>Entering Automaton Mode</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/entering-automaton-mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/entering-automaton-mode/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Focus Mode Persistence</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/focus-mode-persistence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/focus-mode-persistence/</guid><description>As of June 2022, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to query the currently active Focus Mode.
A strategy to achieve similar functionality is to add Shortcut Automations for every Focus Mode such that:
A file in iCloud contains the name of the currently active Focus Mode Whenever a Focus Mode mode is activated, its name is written to the file Whenever a Focus Mode mode is deactivated, a None is written to the file Shortcuts Set Focus Mode Unset Focus Mode Get Focus Mode Write Variable Shortcut Read Variable Shortcut</description></item><item><title>Life Is All About Maintenance</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/life-is-all-about-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/life-is-all-about-maintenance/</guid><description>Life is all about maintenance. Your body, your house, your relationships; everything requires constant and never-ending maintenance.</description></item><item><title>Not Wanting to Bother Others is Powerful</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/not-wanting-to-bother-others-is-powerful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/not-wanting-to-bother-others-is-powerful/</guid><description>For a lot of people, bothering others is acutely unpleasant. Just the fear of being unpleasant alone can create a lot of anxiety.
The good news is that this can be harnessed to good purposes. One of the keys to be faithful to a commitment is to involve others. This is one of the many reasons why adding a social component to an activity can drastically increase the motivation to keep it up.</description></item><item><title>Personal Knowledge Database</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/personal-knowledge-database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/personal-knowledge-database/</guid><description>A personal knowledge database (PKB) is a collection of interlinked notes with no particular schema.</description></item><item><title>Reserve Punishments for Critical Habits Only</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/reserve-punishments-for-critical-habits-only/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/reserve-punishments-for-critical-habits-only/</guid><description>Punishing oneself for a misstep is a dangerous strategy.
With time, the punishment itself might be just factored in as the &amp;ldquo;price of sin&amp;rdquo;: something accounted for and explicitly decided to be worth it.
Prefer positive reinforcement for the majority of willpower challenges and reserve the use of the stick for key habits that may have a cascading effect (e.g waking up).</description></item><item><title>Start the Day With an Adrenaline Rush</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/start-the-day-with-an-adrenaline-rush/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/start-the-day-with-an-adrenaline-rush/</guid><description>Not Wanting to Bother Others is Powerful.
Reserve Punishments for Critical Habits Only.</description></item><item><title>TBD Title - Assume Nothing</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/tbd-title--assume-nothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/tbd-title--assume-nothing/</guid><description>#TODO</description></item><item><title>The ENCODE Framework</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/the-encode-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/the-encode-framework/</guid><description>A framework for note-taking used in Personal Knowledge Database systems. The acronym stands for Encounter, Note, Connect, Organize, Develop, Express.
That&amp;rsquo;s interesting&amp;hellip; That reminds me of&amp;hellip; That belongs with&amp;hellip; This can be incremented a bit! Do I want more of this?</description></item><item><title>Wake Up At The Same Time Every Day</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/wake-up-at-the-same-time-every-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/wake-up-at-the-same-time-every-day/</guid><description>Use the current baseline as starting point. It&amp;rsquo;s more important to be consistent than to be early. The first objective is to get the circadian rhythm in place so it can serve as foundation to a stable routine. To that end, there are two obvious-but-hard-to-execute factors: being disciplined with bedtime and actually booting up at the planned time.
Bedtime Discipline The straightforward metric to track would be a direct measure of adherence to the scheduled start of the bedtime period.</description></item><item><title>Willpower</title><link>https://victor.villas/systematist/willpower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/systematist/willpower/</guid><description>The hurdles when following the good path Stimulus Rush We are equipped with various legacy rewards mechanisms that companies learned how to manipulate to the point of abuse. Porn, games, drugs, social networks, junk food. Many products maximize the stimuli and overshoot the healthy thresholds of our built-in reward systems, creating vice and hurting our self control. Slippery Slope Very tightly planned routines are also very unstable because they have a greater attack surface for unforeseen circumstances.</description></item></channel></rss>