<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>🌐 Internetizen on Victor's Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/</link><description>Recent content in 🌐 Internetizen on Victor's Website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://victor.villas/internetizen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create Your Own Website</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/create-your-own-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/create-your-own-website/</guid><description>Deploying a website into your domain is the foundation for your presence on the Web. Control over its content is what makes it yours, the content itself is what makes it represent you.
There are many ways to create and operate a website: from all-inclusive builders like WordPress, to online hosting a Static Website, to self-hosting a fully-fledged web server.
Simple: Website Builder Platforms Flexible: Free Static Website Hosting A cheap way to operate a website is to use static website hosting, which is often offered freely by several platforms like GitHub, GitLab, Netlify, CloudFlare, DigitalOcean and many others.</description></item><item><title>DNS Server</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/dns-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/dns-server/</guid><description>A Domain Name System Server is a piece of Internet infrastructure responsible for translating domain names into to a collection of servers (by their IP addresses) to which requests must be forwarded.
A DNS server might not have the translation available for every domain, so they can communicate with other trusted DNS servers. Domain Registrars usually manage their own DNS servers to allow clients to configure their domains.</description></item><item><title>Domain Registrar</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/domain-registrar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/domain-registrar/</guid><description>A domain name registrar is an organization that manages the reservation of Internet domain names, supervised by the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN).
Most registrars will also offer authoritative DNS hosting so their clients can make use of the domain, though this is not implied from the registrar role.
There are several registrars with similarly good prices and user experience: Hover, Gandi.net, Freenom, Porkbun, NameCheap, DNSimle, Google Domains etc.</description></item><item><title>IndieAuth</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/indieauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/indieauth/</guid><description>IndieAuth is a protocol for Web Sign-In. It&amp;rsquo;s a standard on top of OAuth that defines how to obtain an OAuth 2.0 Bearer Token for an End-User represented solely by an URL.
The protocol inspects your website for metadata that specifies which authentication endpoint you want to use and then proceeds with the OAuth token negotiation with that endpoint.
Supporting IndieAuth in a service means letting users bring their own authentication provider.</description></item><item><title>Internet Domain Name</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/internet-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/internet-domain-name/</guid><description>An Internet Domain Name is a (supposedly) human-readable string that identifies an entity on the Internet, e.g. wikipedia.org.
Every domain is a name under a Top-Level Domain (TLD). For example, the domain johndoe.net is the johndoe name under the net TLD.
The way to own a domain is to purchase it with a Domain Registrar for an annual fee. TLDs and registrars are regulated by IANA/ICANN.
A domain is yours as long as you pay the fees for it and unless you&amp;rsquo;re legally obliged to stop using it due to some drastic reason.</description></item><item><title>Own Your Internet Domain Name</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/own-your-internet-domain-name/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/own-your-internet-domain-name/</guid><description>Having your own personal Internet Domain Name is the first step towards building an identity and setting up your own corner of the Web. A domain costs money, but a cheap one costs as much as a telephone number.
Because the domain serves as a foundation to your online identity, it should be chosen carefully and considered permanent. There are a few tools that can help you choosing your domain name and others that can quickly search under which TLDs that name is available.</description></item><item><title>RelMeAuth</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/relmeauth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/relmeauth/</guid><description>RelMeAuth is a protocol for Web Sign-In. This protocol inspects your website for links to other identities of yours that could be used for authentication.
For example, these can be links to your profile on some platform like GitHub or social media like Twitter. If the service confirms such profile belongs to the same person that operates this website, the protocol knows that it can use this service&amp;rsquo;s authentication to confirm your identity.</description></item><item><title>Set Up a Web Sign-In Method</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/set-up-a-web-signin-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/set-up-a-web-signin-method/</guid><description>If you already Use a Custom Email Address, a simple method is to use email authentication supported by RelMeAuth.
RelMeAuth might support one of the platforms or social networks you have an account, but consider a bonus independence point not relying on those to authenticate you anywhere.
Additionally, configuring IndieAuth with IndieAuth.com for authorization will allow you to use your email-based RelMeAuth to sign in to websites that don&amp;rsquo;t support RelMeAuth directly but do support the IndieAuth standard.</description></item><item><title>Static Website With Hugo</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/static-website-with-hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/static-website-with-hugo/</guid><description>Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators out there.
Bare Bones Setup Basic Templates Base Layout This is used as starting point for pretty much all other pages and should take care of the most generic boilerplate. The template below includes basic responsiveness configurations and very minimal styling.
layouts/_default/baseof.html
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;#34;{{ .Site.LanguageCode }}&amp;#34; dir=&amp;#34;ltr&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;#34;X-UA-Compatible&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;IE=edge&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;#34;UTF-8&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;#34;viewport&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;width=device-width, initial-scale=1&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;icon&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;{{ &amp;#34;favicon.</description></item><item><title>Top-Level Domain</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/toplevel-domain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/toplevel-domain/</guid><description>A top-level domain (TLD) is the last part of a domain name, such as .com, .net, .org.
These are regulated by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA) but operation is delegated to specific organizations depending on the purpose of the TLD.
An exhaustive list of existing TLDs can be fount at https://www.iana.org/domains/root/db. No every Domain Registrar is licensed to offer every existing TLD.</description></item><item><title>Use a Custom Email Address</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/use-a-custom-email-address/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/use-a-custom-email-address/</guid><description>The most immediate advantage of owning a domain is to be able to customize your email address. Not all e-mail providers support this, but even if yours don&amp;rsquo;t you can also try relying on your Domain Registrar to provide an inbox and/or Email forwarding.
Having all your e-mail coming through an address that you own allows you to change providers without the hassle of notifying all your contacts and updating all your credentials.</description></item><item><title>Web Sign-In</title><link>https://victor.villas/internetizen/web-signin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://victor.villas/internetizen/web-signin/</guid><description>Web Sign-In is an authentication method where the identity is based on a web address. A client that supports Web Sign-In will then inspect the given address to find an authorization method to use as next step.
One common implementation of Web Sign-In is RelMeAuth, which uses rel=me links to find a service to which authentication can be delegated. Another option is IndieAuth, where the client negotiates with a specified authorization endpoint.</description></item></channel></rss>